<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-29T23:44:59+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">HorseyBlog</title><subtitle>A little oasis for my thoughts and projects.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New gear and changes to the EDC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/08/29/New-gear-and-changes-to-the-EDC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New gear and changes to the EDC" /><published>2019-08-29T15:40:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-08-29T15:40:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/08/29/New%20gear%20and%20changes%20to%20the%20EDC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/08/29/New-gear-and-changes-to-the-EDC.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://horseymask.github.io/personal/2019/07/11/The-EDC.html&quot;&gt;Original everyday carry (EDC) post here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With summer vacation coming to an end, I’ve decided to do some back-to-school shopping on the tech side. This semester is especially going to be travel heavy with no dorm to rely on, so I’ve bought some gear that’ll help me survive the more “road warrior” lifestyle I’ll go through this semester. Also, I’ve thinking of some changes to the EDC for this semester, which I’ll also get into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-new-gear&quot;&gt;The new gear&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-29edcupdate/20190829_144202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bluetooth Keyboard - Logitech K380&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got this keyboard refurbished, which was a great deal. Even if the keys don’t have Korean legends on them, I don’t type that much in Korean nor do I look at the keyboard when I type, so more power to me I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, I was planning to get the Logitech Slim Combo keyboard case, but the case was a lot more expensive than I wanted it to be. The case itself also added way too much bulk to the iPad, which was a bit unsightly. Worries about the kickstand and how well it’ll hold up from long sessions with the Apple Pencil was the final straw. From there, I looked to just get a cheaper, more universal bluetooth keyboard that I can use with devices other than the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back to the K380. Right now I’m typing this entry up on the iPad with the K380, and it’s not as bad as an experience that I thought it would be. I usually use a mechanical keyboard most of the time, and while comparing this keyboard to a mechanical one is unfair, the tactile feedback is quite acceptable, especially on the go. It’s definitely a productivity booster on the iPad, and makes the iPad a more formidable laptop replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue that I did face while typing is the circular keycap shapes. While it’s not as big of a deal as I make it, the circular keycaps does somewhat impact my typing speed and accuracy, as I am used to square keycaps. Also, the keyboard is a bit more low profile and lower that I am comfortable with, making typing a bit harder. Both of these things are probably stuff that I can get used to over time, so I think that I just need more time with this keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External Battery - Xiaomi Mi Power Bank 3 Pro, 20000mAh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one just arrived yesterday, along with a Quick Charge 3.0 (QC 3.0) + USB PD charging brick. While I didn’t really feel a need for a battery bank before, as I always had access to an outlet near me, whether it was at home, or at a dorm. But, with my phone’s battery draining a lot faster than the start of the first semester, and more time on the road this semester, I thought I’d need it this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first wanted a 26800mAh battery, as it allows for the most battery capacity while still being able to take on an airplane, but they turned out to be a lot rarer on the Korean markets. So I just settled with Xiaomi’s latest 20000mAh battery bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the spec sheet, the USB-A ports does look to match QC 3.0 standards, and the USB-C port supports USB-PD, which allows up to 45W of power delivery. This was what sold me, as I did want to have a battery bank that could support charging a laptop on the go. Though my current laptop doesn’t support USB-PD charging (I think), I thought it would be useful for the future. The USB-C will come in handy for charging my iPad though, as it does support USB-PD quick charging, and for my phone, which supports both QC and USB-PD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to put it to the test with the school year and facing conditions when I need to use it, but so far, it feels like a solid battery bank that I could rely on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-proposed-changes&quot;&gt;The (proposed) changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laptop: &lt;del&gt;ASUS Zenbook UX310UQ&lt;/del&gt; No laptop at all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds crazy, right? A CS Student without a laptop on the go while studying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hear me out here though. I did say it was proposed changes. Nothing is final here. I realized that my laptop itself is pretty hefty with all the other stuff in my EDC bag. With a lot of movement expected next semester, I thought to myself if I could lessen the weight of the stuff I carry everyday, I can save a lot of effort while moving around. And so, I thought of taking my laptop out of my everyday carry in favor of the iPad, especially with the addition of the Logitech K380 keyboard, and possibly a wireless moue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are limitations with this choice. While the iPad is great for taking notes, drawing, writing (with a keyboard) and other kinds of lighter productivity tasks, there is one caveat: coding.  By itself, the iPad is very limited into code compilation and resources. There are certain apps such as Pythonista that does allow some coding, but there still is a lot of limitations, such as coding language choice. While iPadOS did make strides into making the iPad a laptop replacement, coding is still hard on it. I could also host a remote Visual Studio Code environment to use anywhere with the iPad, but that takes a lot of effort and also requires constant internet access. In the meantime, while I’m connected to the school network, I can SSH to write and compile my code using Vim on the university’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these limitations, I am planning to go through a week of using the iPad as my main device, when school starts. A lot of other people have tried doing this, with varying degrees of success depending on what their profession is and what their requirements were. I want to see how using the iPad as their main device as a CS student would be like. Taking it a step further, I can also ditch the desktop and only use the iPad as my computer device for the week. I know it probably won’t be very easy with all the limitations that I didn’t foresee, but I think it would be a great experience and a trial to see if the iPad can actually replace my laptop on an everyday carry basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other random bits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also decided to throw my old Magic Mouse that I purchased way back, as iPadOS now has mouse support, albeit pretty poor support. The scroll gestures don’t work for the Magic Mouse yet, and I guess that’s what I get for purchasing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the big proposed changes, there was a wallet change to a more compact one that is more focused on cards rather than bills. Very uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also was playing with the idea of a smartwatch, but the side of not investing in one is mostly winning just due to the price. The Galaxy Watch Active 2 did look pretty good though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-29edcupdate/20190829_152950.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the final image of my updated EDC. I kept the ASUS laptop in there for now because it still isn’t out just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that all from me this time with the updates.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Original everyday carry (EDC) post here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Games I’ve been playing - CrossCode and Factorio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/games/2019/08/22/Some-games.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Games I've been playing - CrossCode and Factorio" /><published>2019-08-22T02:41:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-08-22T02:41:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/games/2019/08/22/Some-games</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/games/2019/08/22/Some-games.html">&lt;p&gt;The first summer vacation of university is here, and after working on some university stuff from June to July, I met August with the most free time I’ve had in a while. To wind down from the burn-out from June to July, I’ve started to play some games in my Steam library that I bought but haven’t touched in a while. While doing so, I basically opened a Pandora’s Box of sinking a bunch of time into two particular games that I wanted to write about today. These two games, as seen from the title, are Factorio and CrossCode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being honest here, I still haven’t finished both games (Not that you really ever finish Factorio though), so I can’t give a complete review for both games. But after a week of sinking time into both and enjoying them both, I wanted to write something about my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;crosscode&quot;&gt;CrossCode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-22crossfactorio/20190822022312_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
CrossCode was a game that I didn’t have much expectations for before playing. In fact, I never knew that this game was a thing until I heard Linus from LinusTechTips talk about it on a livestream when asked for some games he was playing at the time. With that single entry point, I decided to buy it during this year’s summer sale, and haven’t really played it until now. But after about a week of playing and having tested the waters enough, I can say I’m enjoying it a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You play as Lea, a player of &lt;em&gt;CrossWorlds&lt;/em&gt;, a virtual MMORPG. Due to various circumstances that I haven’t reached in the story as of now, her speech functions in the game have malfunctions, leading her to only speak in certain phrases. While playing the main story path of CrossWorlds, you meet various supporting characters along the way, such as Emilie and C’tron, that are charming in their own ways. While I haven’t finished the full story of the game, there haven’t been any real antagonists or have seen any final objectives of the game, but so far, I’ve seen some great progress in the story, such as tidbits of Lea’s identity. It’s kind of mysterious, honestly, as I can feel there is something underlying the mostly cheery storylines I’ve been experiencing so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this plot, I feel like CrossCode really shines in the gameplay. The basics of combat come in 4 forms: melee, ranged, dash, and guard. With all of these basics, CrossCode enhances with special abilities called combat arts and elemental forms. Combat arts allow more powerful moves to be performed from all 4 combat basics. Most of these  for melee, ranged, and dash that I’ve seen can be categorized as either large AoE attacks that distributes damage equally or focused, more damaging attacks for one foe. Guard arts are mostly dedicated to well, self-protection as expected. These combat arts are earned with leveling up and using skill points to level up either Lea or unlock new combat arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-22crossfactorio/mpv_9lbJVhY79P.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charging a melee attack, one of the combat arts.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elemental forms open up even more abilities to Lea with alternative combat arts and characteristics. These forms are gradually unlocked along the story, and so far I’ve unlocked 2 of 4, which are heat and ice. While adding new combat arts that are unlocked with separate skill points,, Elemental forms also introduce attack resistances and weaknesses types to the gameplay. For example, a heat based form attack would allow more damage done to an ice-based enemy, and so on. There’s a lot of ways to mix elemental forms on the fly while in combat that I haven’t mastered at all. Simply put, there’s just a lot of strategy that can be implemented in the combat of CrossCode. Or you can just throw that all in the bin and do as you please. It’ll still probably work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also another standout of CrossCode is the level and map design. The levels of the world are a mix of 2D and 3D, where the world itself is 2D, but height is a factor to level design as to what kind of areas you can access. For example, there are some areas that you cannot access unless you are on a surface at a certain height. Therefore, climbing and parkouring around the levels is a key feature of the exploration of worlds, especially if you want all the hidden chests in an area. Also, the puzzles in the levels, especially in the dungeons, can be pretty challenging. I had to search up some walkthroughs for the solution for a certain part of the level, and felt dumb afterwords after how simple the solution was. However, the puzzles did feel rewarding after you found the solution by yourself as you spent more time on the puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-22crossfactorio/mpv_O6bxOSoR7m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of one of the starting areas. The different heights of the map can be seen.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphics and music also are great and fit the purpose of the game. As a game looking to reenact retro games with the graphics, the pixel art style hits the spot, and yet still manages to be detailed enough to be seen as a intended design choice and not to be “lazy” as some people may see the pixel artstyle. The soundtrack doesn’t go towards retro chiptune styled songs, but that’s fine by me, as the music fits each area of the world you are in, as well as the combat situation you are in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I don’t really like about CrossCode is the length of some of the levels, especially the dungeons. While having a long and fleshed out story going with the game is always great, there are times where I did feel that the game was getting a bit tiring to play. In some dungeons, I felt like it should have ended a while ago, yet there were still a lot more keys and puzzles to unlock before I can approach the final boss. Maybe I’m just no good at the game, but that’s just what I felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that point aside, the highs of CrossCode are high, and I feel like for anyone looking for a charming 2D RPG with surprisingly deep combat mechanics and a pretty good story, I can recommend CrossCode, especially if they are a fan of the retro artstyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;factorio&quot;&gt;Factorio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-22crossfactorio/20190822023053_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
Ah, Factorio. This “game” is better fit of the title of one of the biggest time eaters you’ll even start. On a first glance, it looks like a dull game that looks like it belongs in the bargain bin, but as you play, you start to forget the time passing, and before you know it, all you can see is a spaghetti of conveyer belts, inefficient resource management, and constantly running out of coal for your steam engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting off with the (almost) nonexistent: Story. There’s a campaign of around 4 levels that serve as tutorials, that kind of piece together a story. But seriously, all you need to know is: you’re stranded on some planet. You need to escape. Launch a rocket starting with almost nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphics are also a very deemphasized area of the game, with washed out colors and simple colors used. But that’s all that Factorio needs. It’s all about the functionality of your factory, not how it looks. Music is also somewhat forgotten about for me, as I tend to just listen to podcasts in the background and not the ingame music, but others do seem to like the music a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that put, the gameplay elements of this game is almost bottomless. You start simple enough, with mining coal, iron, and copper, and using those basic materials to start building a factory that produces and consumes electricity, creates products, and performs research with the final aim to launch the rocket. Speaking of research, While doing this, your main objective throughout the game will be to perform research by creating science packs. Each research advances to more weapons, products, and kinds of science packs, which require more complex crafting recipes. Before you know it, there’s an overwhelming amount of ingame resources that you’ll be juggling around to try to create these science packs and do research. Oh, and the midst of all of this, you need to protect your factory from hostile enemies on the planet you’re on, and they really don’t take the pollution you’re causing from your factory. With a more complex factory comes more energy usage, which usually comes with more pollution, and therefore more enemies to fight off against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With complexity increasing, automation is key, and there is a bunch of resources at your disposal to accomplish this—whether you decide to take advantage of all of them is your choice. There are assembling machines, robots, trains, circuitry, and much more. I couldn’t even figure out how to get an automated train system to work out in my factory, let alone touch the robots. You’re going to be looking at a lot of tutorials and the wiki while playing this game for the first time, that’s for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also with increasing complexity follows dropping efficiency. As your factory grows, you start to forget about some parts of your factory until it’s too late, and then you realize that the once efficient system you built when things were simpler is now a bottleneck. Rebuilding is painful, but a necessary part of Factorio, at least on your first run, and constant search for the most efficient systems often lead to a completely different factory structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Factorio’s post-endgame is hilariously huge. Even after the rocket launch, there are so much other new things that one can go after. Things like launching more rockets, nuclear power are just some things you can pursue even after you finished your final objective. Also, the modding community for Factorio is also pretty big, and you can always find a new mod to spice up the endgame with even more tasks. You can also find mods that completely enhance the game to feature new gameplay mechanics and resources, which just increases the complexity even further. Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here comes one issue with the game for me. I tended to want to give up on the current mess of a factory that I had and start over. Sometimes this is a ok idea, as you would have learned from the mistakes of the horrible spaghetti monster you have constructed, and could (hopefully) make a better factory by starting over. However, this isn’t great when you’re 20 hours deep into a single factory. Interest can be lost in the current factory, while starting a new map just seems insane. This can be remedied with pure determination and love for sinking more time into your factory, but sometimes it can feel very daunting to do so. I guess a break is always a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you need a giant time sink of a “game” that can suck the remaining life that you have into micromanaging a virtual factory to achieve peak efficiency, grab a couple of podcasts and sit down. Factorio is a ride that’ll keep you busy for hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-22crossfactorio/20190822023111_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My hilariously messy factory.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a long writeup for both of these games that I’ve been really into over this August. Almost forgot to finish writing this up due to wanting to continue playing. But there it is, my thoughts of two awesome games. Hope you get to try one of these games, or both of them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first summer vacation of university is here, and after working on some university stuff from June to July, I met August with the most free time I’ve had in a while. To wind down from the burn-out from June to July, I’ve started to play some games in my Steam library that I bought but haven’t touched in a while. While doing so, I basically opened a Pandora’s Box of sinking a bunch of time into two particular games that I wanted to write about today. These two games, as seen from the title, are Factorio and CrossCode.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kyoto Animation and me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/anime/2019/07/30/Kyoani.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kyoto Animation and me" /><published>2019-07-30T01:50:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-30T01:50:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/anime/2019/07/30/Kyoani</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/anime/2019/07/30/Kyoani.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/7-30kyoani/kyoanihq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of the HQ of Kyoto Animations that I took on my trip to Kyoto.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to think of how I wanted to write this blog post, and I’m still not very sure how I’d want to structure it. But here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kyoto-animation---the-one-and-only&quot;&gt;Kyoto Animation - the one and only&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When many people are asked what their favorite anime studio is, a great amount of names come up. There’s a lot of famous ones, such as Studio Ghibli and Madhouse that are loved by many for various reasons. But one name stands out for me, as it does for many others. Kyoto Animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyoto Animation, shortened to Kyoani by many (as I will in this post), is a gem within the anime industry, both in their anime projects and their system of work. Approaching how Kyoani works first as a studio, the main difference between Kyoani and other anime studios is that everyone working for Kyoani is hired full-time. Most people working at other studios are more like freelancers, jumping from project to project, sometimes for different studios as well. Hence, they are usually paid by each project they accomplish. However, Kyoani’s employees are all on payroll, working with a monthly salary. This may sound extremely basic, but in the anime industry, this is unheard of. This basically ends up making a job at Kyoani much more stable. In a world of terrible working conditions for animators in the anime industry, Kyoani was a shining beacon of difference in working environments for anime studios. A role model for other studios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a role model Kyoani was for their quality of work. Every anime project, TV, Movie, OVA, or anything else in between, has always shown the highest quality of art, animation, and sound that was available. For example, the work and attention to detail in Violet Evergarden, a Kyoani production, was simply impeccable, and that alone made it a marvel to watch. Other works, such as K-ON and The Melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya are no exception, and this attention to detail that Kyoani has always makes every anime special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t just the production value, but also the content of writing of the works. What should be a mundane slice-of-life view of someone’s life always looked fun, lively, and yet comfy in anime like K-ON, Tamako Market, and Lucky Star. Other anime took this slice-of-life and turned it to intriguing mystery, such as The Melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya and Hyouka. Finally, in Nichijou, it took slice-of-life into a wacky, slapstick comedy that never failed to get laughs. Other Kyoani productions took more emotional paths, such as CLANNAD, A Silent Voice, and Violet Evergarden, that makes watching each minute harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mixture allowed Kyoani to make anime that I found to always be a must watch. Kyoani took existing source materials and flipped them into animated masterpieces of their own,and in some cases, went above and beyond the source. Out of the 12 animes that I gave a perfect 5 stars on my list, 9 of them are Kyoani productions. I wanted to write about one in particular that impacted me greatly, that being Liz and the Blue Bird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;liz-and-the-blue-bird&quot;&gt;Liz and the Blue Bird&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liz and the Blue Bird is a movie of a side story off of Sound Euphonium, another anime project based on a light novel that Kyoani has worked on. The movie’s main focus is on the relationship between the two main characters, Mizore and Nozomi. The two are set to play a duet of a music piece named Liz and the Blue Bird, a piece based off a fairy tale on the relationship of a bird and a girl. Throughout the hardships of practicing the song, the movie shows the relationship between Mizore and Nozomi are challenged, and throughout allusions to the fairy tale and other motifs such as university and going on separate paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many audiences and critics didn’t like Liz and the Blue Bird. Some people thought it was just boring, without much substance to go on (as many people think about some Kyoani works). Others thought the drama and tension between Mizore and Nozomi’s friendship was too weak to be significant. However, this movie affected me greatly, especially due to the circumstances that I was going through at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went to watch this movie at theatres at October, I was fresh off graduating from high school, and separated from long friends across borders. Another significant issue was that I still didn’t have a university to go to. Having been rejected from every school so far, I was still waiting until the end of December for final waitlist results. My best friend especially hit me hard, already being in the middle of his semester at a university that I could only dream of getting into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While watching the movie, I felt a lot like Mizore, feeling uncertain about the future, feeling like I was falling behind of my best friend, who could only be drawn parallels to Nozomi at this point. But most of all, I asked the same question that Mizore did: Am I the Blue Bird, not wanting to let go to the past and friends, or am I Liz, who can let go of the Blue Bird, for the bird’s own good? Liz and the Blue Bird really did help me learn that regardless of the past and others, I needed to carve my own path that works for me. While friends are great, ultimately I need to make the choices for my own path for myself. With the uncertainty that I was going through at the time, I really needed this lesson, and Liz and the Blue Bird was able to teach me this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from personal connections, the art, music, and other production values for Liz and the Blue Bird worked perfectly for me. It strayed off from the original artstyle of Sound Euphonium, and sticked to a more watercolor style, which I loved. I especially thought it fit well with the fairy tale setting of Liz and the Blue Bird, making it feel like a picturebook. All the character designs, while more simpler than its Sound Euphonium counterparts, had its own charm and beauty. The music, especially the duet performances of Mizore and Nozomi, were also great, not only in quality, but also telling the story. From the unsynced performances at the start to the great final performance of the duet at the end, it really showed the relationship of the two change throughout the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Kyoani works, such as A Silent Voice, do stand out more than Liz and the Blue Bird on its own. And I do agree those works are brilliant, having given A Silent Voice a 5 star rating as well. But in my personal circumstances that I had when I entered the movie theatre that day, Liz and the Blue Bird just clicked for me. I never felt more relatable to a movie, and I thoroughly enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all comes in reflection to the tragic arson incident at Kyoani’s Studio 1. With the death count at 35, and with some key names of Kyoani’s directors being revealed as deceased, I’m still honestly in denial. Beyond the tragedy of lost of lives, some of the best talent in animation in the world were erased in a single, terrible accident. While Kyoani will surely not go down from this incident, I do feel like it would be a while until they get back on their feet, and I wish them all the best in recovery.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The EDC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/07/12/The-EDC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The EDC" /><published>2019-07-12T03:36:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T03:36:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/07/12/The-EDC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/07/12/The-EDC.html">&lt;p&gt;To start this blog with actual meaningful content, I thought that I’d just go over my everyday carry, or EDC. It’s basically the stuff that I usually have on me on a daily basis if I’m going anywhere outside the house. Usually this would vary between if I’m just out meeting someone, or I’m headed to a class or out expecting to do actual work. With the list of stuff, I’ll just give a mini-review of each item that I would carry around and use every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bare-minimum&quot;&gt;The bare minimum&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I’d carry if I’m traveling around where a lot of luggage would hamper my experience or otherwise be unnecessary, or if there’s a danger that I’d lose something. Some scenarios would be going out to meet some friends, running small errands, or just a short walk outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phone: Samsung Galaxy S9+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mobile phone of choice. Still consider it the last Android phone that keeps the design choices that I hold important, the most important two being no notches and including the 3.5mm headphones jack. Storage flexibility with the micro-SD card slot earns brownie points for flexibility, but I got the 256GB model in the first place, so I found little use for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things hardware-wise, the Exynos 9810 hasn’t failed me in any usage case yet, with no slowdowns bad enough that I remember of. Also, the extra battery size on the S9+ is also great, and to my personal use, the phone lasts me the whole day and then some. However, I’m not really a heavy smartphone user, so my experience may be vastly different to yours. Finally, the OLED screen, following Samsung trends, is great and accurate enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much of a camera guy in the first place, so the cameras on the S9+ is great, and I doubt I’d actually need more camera power then I have on this phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software wise, I really like One UI, Samsung’s Android implementation, as I’m personally a fan of the design choices made. One UI having more features added to Android is just icing on the cake, such as screenshot options. Though I do still use Nova Launcher as my default launcher to replace the stock One UI launcher, just because I’m just more used to my setup on Nova Launcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Galaxy S9+ is basically my ideal phone for now, until the industry changes trends and actually puts back headphone jacks and no notches on the table. Notches may be gone with more technological advances in glass and display technology, but I’m not so sure for the headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallet: Smartphone &amp;amp; Phone case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m traveling light, I rarely find the need to store paper money or a large selection of cards at all. I’ve grown used to mobile payment systems, like Samsung Pay, so I don’t find much use in a wallet in a light travel situation. When I do need to make a physical payment, the phone case that I use that has room for one card suffices. I just keep my student ID in there, which doubles as a debit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch: Swatch New Gent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the best watch, I know. Blame the 10 year old me that picked it out and never actually really wore it. Just got back into wearing a watch on my EDC, and guess this was the only choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the timetelling is still accurate when correctly set. Just getting it perfectly set, right to the second is pretty challenging sometimes, if you really want to be precise. However, the date mechanism on the watch is always a day late, with no amount of adjusting getting it to be fixed. That always bugs me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, since I’m not that much of a watch enthusiast, and since I still dig the orange/black color scheme, I think the watch just suits me fine. As long as it can tell the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earphones/IEM : VSonic GR07 Classic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent upgrade from my ATH-IM70. I was looking for a sub-100$ upgrade, and by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://crinacle.com/ranking-list/&quot;&gt;crinacle’s list&lt;/a&gt; and looking at the graphs frequency graphs, I came to the conclusion that the GR07 would be the best fit, and it was a great choice. Chi-Fi may be cheaper, but as long as the quality is there, I’m fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I love good audio, I can’t trust myself to give a detailed review of audio products, and therefore I’ll just end it by saying that the GR07s are great for any song that I listen it with. I find it as a great jack-of-all-trades IEM that I’m happy with listening to anything with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accessory kit that came with it, while including a lot of stuff, wasn’t the best fit for me. The earhooks were too big for my small ears, and I ended up just using the wire as hooks. The foam eartips were fine, not Comply foam, but the isolation is good and seems like the material will laster longer than Comply. I appreciated the large selection of eartips as well. Finally, I don’t use the included carrying case at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-complete-set&quot;&gt;The complete set&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This EDC kit would be if I’m going somewhere to get actual work done, such as going to a class. It can also be used if I’m going to be out all day, and I don’t know what I would need while on the road. This EDC kit is inclusive of the previous “the bare minimum” kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallet : Kipling Wallet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more room to carry things in this kit, I do carry a wallet around in my backpack, but it is still rarely used. It holds my ID, other debit cards that I use much less often, as well as cash for emergencies when I would need it. I still either use Samsung Pay, or my card on my S9 case first, so the payment options here are just backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laptop : ASUS Zenbook UX310U&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually bought this laptop on a whim when my old MacBook Pro from 2010 was simply too slow for any tasks, with the keyboard being broken just another reason to get an upgrade. Was looking into getting a ThinkPad, but with the stores I visited not having any, I decided to go with this ASUS laptop. With a i7-7500U, the laptop is fast enough for any task that I need to do on the go, whether that be typing an essay or doing coding assessments. The GeForce 940MX is also just fast enough for any random indie game that I feel like playing at the time, or if I feel for a quick round of TF2. I don’t game on the go often, so it works in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly though, the main reason I got this laptop is the ability to have a HDD + SSD combo in a laptop. Really like this feature, as I still listen to music from files, and I like having a cheap storage option like a HDD, even on a laptop. This feature on a relatively thin laptop turned this otherwise generic laptop into the perfect laptop for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with the rise of laptop CPUs with more cores, and Intel’s CPU issues with security and hyperthreading, I have been thinking of getting a new laptop to replace this one soon. For me, the new ThinkPads with AMD mobile CPUs are looking really attractive. Now only if they had room for a HDD + SSD combo…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pencilcase : Nomadic PE-09&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually managed to never lose this pencilcase for like 4 years now. Guess it’s just a testament to how much I like it. The pencilcase is huge, which allows me to carry all my stationary items that I might need, and then some. Some highlights here is my Lamy Safari, Pentel GraphGear 1000, and the Kuru Toga Advance. The Safari is a great starter fountain pen, and (hopefully) the only one I’ll buy. The GraphGear is my go-to mechanical pencil usually, especially for maths and sciences. The Kuru Toga Advance is my backup mechanical pencil, but also for long writing sessions due to its turning point. Other things that I usually carry around in the pencilcase would be a USB drive and the Apple Pencil. Speaking of the Apple Pencil…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tablet : iPad Air, 3rd Generation + Apple Pencil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my new favorites to add to the work EDC. While I am a big fan of Android, the tablet area is, for a lack of a word, miserable. Hence turning to the only Apple product I’d praise - the iPad. Its main purpose is basically leading the forefront of my paperless movement—and it’s really shown in my workflow. Notability, my note-taking app of choice, has taken over both notebooks and scratch paper. Whenever I’m in class, solving math problems, or studying for an exam, Notability is there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the iPad allowed me to grow a new hobby—drawing. Procreate, my drawing app of choice, just makes art fun, and I’ve started to self-learn how to draw. I’ve also pushed myself to actually draw stuff, whether that be fanart of my favorite anime shows or original creations of myself. I’ve also purchased Affinity Design with the intent to try to learn some vector art as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than those two main usages, I don’t really use it much other than occasionally consuming media on it, and I feel like I’m not getting the full potential out of it. But I do feel like for a lot of the other tasks I do, a laptop fits me more when I’m on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I’ve been trying to use the iPad exclusively during class lectures, and honestly, it’s been a game changer. I’ve even thought of buying a keyboard case for it to get even more use out of it. Especially with iPadOS coming soon that’ll deliver a lot of much needed features to the iPad, I feel like the iPad will just get even more useful. If I don’t need a full-blown desktop OS to perform tasks like coding, the iPad can probably be used instead of a laptop in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notebook: TRAVELER’S notebook, Regular size.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have mentioned that I’m starting to go paperless, I still keep this paper notebook along with me wherever I go, just in case I still need paper to write on. The Traveler’s Notebook system allows me to keep 3 separate notebooks all in the same notebook, and I have a lined notebook, a blank notebook, and a monthly calendar. The lined paper would be used for general notes, while the blank paper would be used for random doodles I want to draw on paper. Finally, the monthly calendar is used as a planner to jot down future events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I basically use the LAMY Safari exclusively on this notebook, and the paper quality shows when I use it with the Safari. Even though the paper is thin, there is no bleeding behind, making it a great experience to write or draw on. While it was pretty expensive when I bought it during my trip in Japan, I still highly recommend it if you want a quality notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculator: TI-Nspire CX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started using this graphing calculator in my IB days, and to this day is my calculator of choice. Does most things that I want it to do in mathematics, and if it doesn’t work, it’s probably either that I’m in the wrong, or it needs CAS features. The nSolve function has changed my life, and the powerful graphing features helped me in a pinch to find solutions the normal calculator features couldn’t get. Now if only I didn’t make the mistake of updating the OS, then I could have modified the OS and even install CAS features on it. Bummer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Bottle : Random vacuum flask&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a normal vacuum flask that I picked up at a store. Keeps hot things hot, cold things cold. Does vacuum flask things well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, think that covers all the stuff I’d carry on a regular basis. May have missed stuff here and there, and/or may have upgraded, added, or removed some stuff in the future, so I guess this blog entry will stay a live document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry has gotten way too long, so I’ll end it here. Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To start this blog with actual meaningful content, I thought that I’d just go over my everyday carry, or EDC. It’s basically the stuff that I usually have on me on a daily basis if I’m going anywhere outside the house. Usually this would vary between if I’m just out meeting someone, or I’m headed to a class or out expecting to do actual work. With the list of stuff, I’ll just give a mini-review of each item that I would carry around and use every day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First step</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/07/08/First-step.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First step" /><published>2019-07-08T01:41:55+09:00</published><updated>2019-07-08T01:41:55+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/07/08/First-step</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/07/08/First-step.html">&lt;p&gt;Been thinking of trying out some blogging for a while, and guess this is the first step. Welcome, random person, to the first post of the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a set idea or plan for the blog yet, but the rough idea is just throwing out my thoughts on things that I’m intereted in. Some of those things would mostly be in tech and anime, but hey, there’s always room for more things later. Who knows, some real life stuff make it in here as well, depending on what I’m thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my projects in various areas (terrible coding pieces, etc) would probably make it in here, as well as random art that I figure out to draw. Still learning the ropes, so don’t expect masterpieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that’s all for now I guess, hopefully I don’t quit this within a few weeks or so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Been thinking of trying out some blogging for a while, and guess this is the first step. Welcome, random person, to the first post of the blog.</summary></entry></feed>