<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-20T21:41:12+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">HorseyBlog</title><subtitle>A little oasis for my thoughts and projects.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Distrohopping</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/05/20/Distrohopping.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Distrohopping" /><published>2021-05-20T21:33:00+09:00</published><updated>2021-05-20T21:33:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/05/20/Distrohopping</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/05/20/Distrohopping.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-05-20distro/2021-05-20_21-29.png&quot; alt=&quot;Completed Build&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a bit bored. So I decided to do some distrohopping. Well, to be more exact, I moved away from Windows 10 on my main system to Linux, then I went on a bit of distrohopping adventure, meaning that I tried out a bunch of different Linux distributions, or distros. On the way, I’ve learned a lot, and that with my current habits and usecases for a computer, Linux fits it very well. With this post, I’m looking to go through my process of throwing myself through countless installs (and maybe a few more) to where I finally landed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rationale-to-pack-up-my-bags-and-move&quot;&gt;The rationale to pack up my bags and move&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I made the move away from Windows in the first place, it was mostly due to three factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Privacy concerns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boredom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy concerns has been a great issue from the start of Windows 10, though it’s probably been going on before then. With all sorts of telemetry being collected, it’s been an obvious issue. It can be disabled with some registry changes, or ripped out entiretly from the ISO with unofficial tools, but it’s just not an ideal experience. Lack of control is also a lesser issue, as you could technically wrangle Windows around to do some things that you want it to do. For example, you could technically control Windows Update to make sure you aren’t getting any major updates immediatly as history shows that there are issues with new Windows updates. However, sometimes Windows works again your decisions and installs the updates anyways. Finally, I just got bored of Windows, after using it for so long, and wanted to jump over to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-move-to-the-first-distro---pop_os&quot;&gt;The move to the first distro - Pop!_OS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking around doing my research at the offered distros, I decided to head with Pop!_OS, as it seemed to be a great and easy to use distro with some added features.
Pop!_OS is a Ubuntu based distro developed by the folks at System76, a computer hardware company most well known for their laptops. I hold them to a pretty high regard, and I thought that thier take on Linux would be a great experience. And I was right in that thinking. The little features they added into the Pop!_OS ecosystem were very good, such as the window management system included right in the box. It was a great introduction to an new way of using my desktop space that will soon follow me to the other distros that I tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease of use and compatibility was a welcoming suprise for myself. Previously, due to a bug with my graphics card with the Linux kernel, I was simply unable to use any graphical application at all, which was a huge issue. But after doing some research, I was able to finally fix the issue for myself, and use a Linux setup with a proper desktop. I was also able to run all the apps that I really needed for myself, and everything really did seem to come together quite well. Even the few games that I still play ran very well, native or with Steam’s Proton compatibility layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were still a major issue that I had with this distro: Boredom. While Pop!_OS is a great distro with all the customizations that System76 brought to it, it was still Ubuntu under all the customization. Having used Ubuntu for a short bit before, I still wanted something different. Also, I didn’t really fancy the GNOME desktop environment that it shipped with. I wanted something a bit more simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in no way me trying to disparage Pop!_OS or System76. In fact, I think System76 has a goldmine of a distro on their hands. An easy to use Linux distro with enhancements that enthusiasts would enjoy? Priceless for many. I would recommend it to many as a starting begineer Linux experience, but I was looking for something else. So I started packing up my bags and prepared to move out again to where many move on next: the Arch family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;btw-i-use-arch-manjaro&quot;&gt;btw i use &lt;del&gt;arch&lt;/del&gt; manjaro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stop for my distrohopping ways was Manjaro Linux. I always did want to try out the Arch based distros, but I was always intimidated by the fabled difficulity of installing said distro to a computer that I would use daily. So, as a compromise, I just decided to try out Manjaro first. Along with this, influenced by the window manager features that Pop!_OS spoiled me with, I also decided to try out a full fledged window manager. I decided to use Awesome, as it seemed like an easier window manager to use for a beginner. The Awesomewm Manjaro edition had a customized version of Awesome with a lot of graphical features that I thought catered more towards a beginner. And by trying it out, I was right. I found myself adjusting quite well with Awesome, and while I don’t think I took advantage of all the available features, it was a great first time experience with a window manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to Manjaro as a distro though. Overall, I did enjoy my experience here, but I think that I could have had a better experience had I been better informed. While I was changing distros from Pop!_OS to Manjaro, I was also looking for a less bloated distro, one with only the programs that I needed. Well, the full-fledged Manjaro wasn’t really that. I felt that there was a lot of included software that I did not need, and I didn’t want to start stripping it down to break something else. Meanwhile, the minimal verion of Manjaro was a lot more… well, minimal, but felt like it was missing some important things that I did need. It felt like a messy situation where I needed a bit more control than I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there were a lot of other technical issues, espically with automounting drives and setting up services. While I was able to get my NTFS drives from my Windows installation working, I could not get a Windows dynamic drive set up properly to be automounted. This came down to me not being able to set up the services correctly for the dynamic drive to be automounted, and I could not figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manjaro did teach me some valuable lessons, such as that I wanted to use a window manager, and not rely on a desktop environment. However, with the issues that compounded throughout my experience, it was time to move again. This time though, I thought, ‘What if I go even more simplier, to a barebone installation of Linux so I can install just the stuff I need?’. So instead of going back to a more “done-for-you” distro, I decided to dig myself deeper, and take the jump to proper Arch Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;btw-i-use-arch&quot;&gt;btw i use arch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people who fall in the rabbit hole of Linux eventually find their way to Arch, one way or the other. I was finally able to take the chance here. Installing Arch went a lot more smoother than I initally expected. While everything was done in the command line, from partition and preparing a drive to the actual installation process, it wasn’t as bad as some people make it out to be. By roughly following online guides, I was able to finish up the base installation, albeit with some minor hitches here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing up the installation and booting into the system for the first time, the first real advantage of Arch came out to me instantly: the freedom and control. In all my previous distros, every installation pre-installs some sort of application, and does a lot of default setup for the hardware. Arch completly threw this out and left me with a blank terminal screen. The bare essential software installed, with the bare minimum hardware configurations to get the computer booted. While this can be daunting and require a lot of work for some, this situation was actually quite refreshing. The fact that from here, I can set up my system, install only the software that I need (and want) was a novel concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the freedoms that Arch Linux gave me, it was actually easier to set up my new system than my previous two distros that I tried, believe it or not. With the proper software and right configurations, all my NTFS hard drives were automounting with no issues, unlike Manjaro. With reading the documentation and following the instructions, I had mostly a very smooth experience with everything that mattered. All my programs were more or less working, and I was even able to do things such as set up a parametric equalizer properly with Arch that was a lot harder with other distros. It was truly surprising how everything did work out easily enough, and in the way I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way, I also changed my tiling windows manager away from Awesome. I found that the added features on Awesome in the Manjaro edition to be harder to add by my own, so I decided to just branch off and find other options. I tried two, spectrwm and qtile, and I ended up settling on qtile, due to the usage of a familar language in Python for configuration and the great documentation provided. I do want to go back and give spectrwm another try though, as it does seem like an even more lightweight window manager than qtile. But for now, I am happy with the configuration of qtile that I came up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of this work done, I think I’ve found my place to stay for now. Arch has given me a lot more control over how my operating system works, and I really do like using the system that I configured for myself. I think that I can finally settle down with my OS choice and setup and stop moving around for now, and I’ll put my distrohopping adventures to a pause for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future-with-distrohopping&quot;&gt;The future with distrohopping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I said that I found a good stable place to stop exploring new distros, I do have a few more in mind. One that I really do want to try, but not know if I want to go through the trouble again is Artix Linux. Artix is just the Arch Linux distro, but with the systemd init system ripped out and replaced with alternative systems, such as OpenRC, runit, and s6. The reason that Artix was created was due to a group of Arch users disliking the idea of using systemd for reasons that are beyond the scope of this blogpost. As I have only used distros that have used systemd, I am somewhat curious as to how Artix does things differently, and how different the setup process is with these alternative init systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But until I do get bored of Arch, which I don’t think I will for a while, or unles I sense that my OS is getting bloated, I think I’m sticking with my current setup. Maybe a bit of configuration changes, or a exploration of window managers, but I’m happy for now. For the first time in a while in the Linux world that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to put my dotfiles and configs on a GitHub repository for myself and others (idk who would want to use it but), so look out for that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html">I got a bit bored. So I decided to do some distrohopping. Well, to be more exact, I moved away from Windows 10 on my main system to Linux, then I went on a bit of distrohopping adventure, meaning that I tried out a bunch of different Linux distributions, or distros. On the way, I’ve learned a lot, and that with my current habits and usecases for a computer, Linux fits it very well. With this post, I’m looking to go through my process of throwing myself through countless installs (and maybe a few more) to where I finally landed. The rationale to pack up my bags and move As for why I made the move away from Windows in the first place, it was mostly due to three factors: Lack of control Privacy concerns Boredom Privacy concerns has been a great issue from the start of Windows 10, though it’s probably been going on before then. With all sorts of telemetry being collected, it’s been an obvious issue. It can be disabled with some registry changes, or ripped out entiretly from the ISO with unofficial tools, but it’s just not an ideal experience. Lack of control is also a lesser issue, as you could technically wrangle Windows around to do some things that you want it to do. For example, you could technically control Windows Update to make sure you aren’t getting any major updates immediatly as history shows that there are issues with new Windows updates. However, sometimes Windows works again your decisions and installs the updates anyways. Finally, I just got bored of Windows, after using it for so long, and wanted to jump over to try something new. The move to the first distro - Pop!_OS Looking around doing my research at the offered distros, I decided to head with Pop!_OS, as it seemed to be a great and easy to use distro with some added features. Pop!_OS is a Ubuntu based distro developed by the folks at System76, a computer hardware company most well known for their laptops. I hold them to a pretty high regard, and I thought that thier take on Linux would be a great experience. And I was right in that thinking. The little features they added into the Pop!_OS ecosystem were very good, such as the window management system included right in the box. It was a great introduction to an new way of using my desktop space that will soon follow me to the other distros that I tried. The ease of use and compatibility was a welcoming suprise for myself. Previously, due to a bug with my graphics card with the Linux kernel, I was simply unable to use any graphical application at all, which was a huge issue. But after doing some research, I was able to finally fix the issue for myself, and use a Linux setup with a proper desktop. I was also able to run all the apps that I really needed for myself, and everything really did seem to come together quite well. Even the few games that I still play ran very well, native or with Steam’s Proton compatibility layer. There were still a major issue that I had with this distro: Boredom. While Pop!_OS is a great distro with all the customizations that System76 brought to it, it was still Ubuntu under all the customization. Having used Ubuntu for a short bit before, I still wanted something different. Also, I didn’t really fancy the GNOME desktop environment that it shipped with. I wanted something a bit more simple. This is in no way me trying to disparage Pop!_OS or System76. In fact, I think System76 has a goldmine of a distro on their hands. An easy to use Linux distro with enhancements that enthusiasts would enjoy? Priceless for many. I would recommend it to many as a starting begineer Linux experience, but I was looking for something else. So I started packing up my bags and prepared to move out again to where many move on next: the Arch family. btw i use arch manjaro The next stop for my distrohopping ways was Manjaro Linux. I always did want to try out the Arch based distros, but I was always intimidated by the fabled difficulity of installing said distro to a computer that I would use daily. So, as a compromise, I just decided to try out Manjaro first. Along with this, influenced by the window manager features that Pop!_OS spoiled me with, I also decided to try out a full fledged window manager. I decided to use Awesome, as it seemed like an easier window manager to use for a beginner. The Awesomewm Manjaro edition had a customized version of Awesome with a lot of graphical features that I thought catered more towards a beginner. And by trying it out, I was right. I found myself adjusting quite well with Awesome, and while I don’t think I took advantage of all the available features, it was a great first time experience with a window manager. Back to Manjaro as a distro though. Overall, I did enjoy my experience here, but I think that I could have had a better experience had I been better informed. While I was changing distros from Pop!_OS to Manjaro, I was also looking for a less bloated distro, one with only the programs that I needed. Well, the full-fledged Manjaro wasn’t really that. I felt that there was a lot of included software that I did not need, and I didn’t want to start stripping it down to break something else. Meanwhile, the minimal verion of Manjaro was a lot more… well, minimal, but felt like it was missing some important things that I did need. It felt like a messy situation where I needed a bit more control than I had. Also, there were a lot of other technical issues, espically with automounting drives and setting up services. While I was able to get my NTFS drives from my Windows installation working, I could not get a Windows dynamic drive set up properly to be automounted. This came down to me not being able to set up the services correctly for the dynamic drive to be automounted, and I could not figure it out. Manjaro did teach me some valuable lessons, such as that I wanted to use a window manager, and not rely on a desktop environment. However, with the issues that compounded throughout my experience, it was time to move again. This time though, I thought, ‘What if I go even more simplier, to a barebone installation of Linux so I can install just the stuff I need?’. So instead of going back to a more “done-for-you” distro, I decided to dig myself deeper, and take the jump to proper Arch Linux. btw i use arch A lot of people who fall in the rabbit hole of Linux eventually find their way to Arch, one way or the other. I was finally able to take the chance here. Installing Arch went a lot more smoother than I initally expected. While everything was done in the command line, from partition and preparing a drive to the actual installation process, it wasn’t as bad as some people make it out to be. By roughly following online guides, I was able to finish up the base installation, albeit with some minor hitches here and there. After finishing up the installation and booting into the system for the first time, the first real advantage of Arch came out to me instantly: the freedom and control. In all my previous distros, every installation pre-installs some sort of application, and does a lot of default setup for the hardware. Arch completly threw this out and left me with a blank terminal screen. The bare essential software installed, with the bare minimum hardware configurations to get the computer booted. While this can be daunting and require a lot of work for some, this situation was actually quite refreshing. The fact that from here, I can set up my system, install only the software that I need (and want) was a novel concept. With the freedoms that Arch Linux gave me, it was actually easier to set up my new system than my previous two distros that I tried, believe it or not. With the proper software and right configurations, all my NTFS hard drives were automounting with no issues, unlike Manjaro. With reading the documentation and following the instructions, I had mostly a very smooth experience with everything that mattered. All my programs were more or less working, and I was even able to do things such as set up a parametric equalizer properly with Arch that was a lot harder with other distros. It was truly surprising how everything did work out easily enough, and in the way I wanted. On the way, I also changed my tiling windows manager away from Awesome. I found that the added features on Awesome in the Manjaro edition to be harder to add by my own, so I decided to just branch off and find other options. I tried two, spectrwm and qtile, and I ended up settling on qtile, due to the usage of a familar language in Python for configuration and the great documentation provided. I do want to go back and give spectrwm another try though, as it does seem like an even more lightweight window manager than qtile. But for now, I am happy with the configuration of qtile that I came up with. With all of this work done, I think I’ve found my place to stay for now. Arch has given me a lot more control over how my operating system works, and I really do like using the system that I configured for myself. I think that I can finally settle down with my OS choice and setup and stop moving around for now, and I’ll put my distrohopping adventures to a pause for now. The future with distrohopping While I said that I found a good stable place to stop exploring new distros, I do have a few more in mind. One that I really do want to try, but not know if I want to go through the trouble again is Artix Linux. Artix is just the Arch Linux distro, but with the systemd init system ripped out and replaced with alternative systems, such as OpenRC, runit, and s6. The reason that Artix was created was due to a group of Arch users disliking the idea of using systemd for reasons that are beyond the scope of this blogpost. As I have only used distros that have used systemd, I am somewhat curious as to how Artix does things differently, and how different the setup process is with these alternative init systems. But until I do get bored of Arch, which I don’t think I will for a while, or unles I sense that my OS is getting bloated, I think I’m sticking with my current setup. Maybe a bit of configuration changes, or a exploration of window managers, but I’m happy for now. For the first time in a while in the Linux world that is. I am planning to put my dotfiles and configs on a GitHub repository for myself and others (idk who would want to use it but), so look out for that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meridian Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/04/15/Meridian-Review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meridian Review" /><published>2021-04-15T14:23:53+09:00</published><updated>2021-04-15T14:23:53+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/04/15/Meridian%20Review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/04/15/Meridian-Review.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-04-15meridian/20210429_182538.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Completed Build&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve actually built a keyboard. The last one that I did with soldering was the old HHKB style keyboard that I wrote about here that I built back in August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, I got a new board to build, and it’s actually my first keyboard that I would call high end. Enter the Meridian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-to-the-meridian&quot;&gt;Introduction to the Meridian&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Meridian is a 60%, top-mount, ergonomic keyboard, designed by famed keyboard designer Ai03 in collaboration with a keyboard vendor, Prime Keyboards. It’s primarily based on the Prime E, a 40% ergonomic keyboard layout that was designed by Prime Keyboards, but in a 60% format. The design is basically a keyboard that is split in the middle for each hand, with the keys slightly angled for a more comfortable typing experience. The angle for the Meridian is a less aggressive 8 degrees, compared to the 12 degree  angle bend that is common with other ergonomic boards, such as the Alice layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this layout of keys, the Meridian is an aluminium enclosure with a brass weight inside, and comes with an aluminium plate and a PCB. I got my Meridian in the first round, with a dark gray color option. The Meridian is going to be continuously offered in in-stock drops, but I was lucky enough to get it in the first drop. Getting it shipped here was somewhat of a nightmare, as the keyboard conveniently got caught in the middle of a blizzard. But I was able to thankfully get it here in one place without too many issues outside of little shipping delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-building-experience&quot;&gt;The building experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building experience was mostly great and straightforward, except for a few issues that I ran into that was probably only in my unit. The main issue I found was the screws. The screws that came with the keyboard were Allen key screws, which was somewhat of an issue as my screwdriver didn’t work very well with the screws. I did have the right Allen screw bit, but the screws were screwed in quite tight by default. One screw in particular was stripped quite badly. So bad in fact, that the threads were stripped and in trying to remove it, I also stripped the head of the screw in the process. With the screw hole being recessed and inaccessible with pliers, and without other equipment to get the screw out, I had to uncomfortably use some elbow grease to… Let’s not get into the violent details, shall we? The point is, I had a very hard time with that one screw, and ended up with a very scuffed case at the end. Thankfully, it isn’t visible during normal use, and that’s good enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue came with my choice to do something called “mill-maxing” my keyboard PCB. This job is to solder on something called Mill-Max sockets into the holes of the PCBs to convert the PCB for hotswapping. There are many reasons why one would want to do this, the largest reason being the flexibility that a hotswappable keyboard gives. The actual job of soldering a Mill-Max socket isn’t too hard. Just insert the sockets on the right side, secure the sockets with a piece of  Kapton tape or a keyboard switch, flip the PCB over, and carefully solder the socket. However, one can easily mess up the soldering job and have solder get in the socket, rendering it useless. When this happens, one has to desolder the socket, which can be a challenge. I had quite the difficulty trying to desolder a socket, as the socket kept on getting stuck while I tried to push it out, as the solder cooled before I could push it out. Resoldering a new one also proved a challenge, as the hole still had remnants of solder left in the hole. I ended up heating up the socket with my iron while trying to push the socket in the hole, which barely worked at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from these issues though, the build went without a hitch, and at the end, I had a perfectly functioning hotswappable Meridian ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modifications&quot;&gt;Modifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There wasn’t too much to modify with this keyboard, but I did add a bit of sound dampening material and replaced the default aluminium plate with a FR4 plate. I added the sound dampener as I thought that the Meridian sounded a bit too hollow stock. With the white felt material that I added, the Meridian sounded a lot better and the hollowness was greatly alleviated. I changed to a FR4 plate as well, as I prefer a bit of flex with my typing experience, and the FR4 material allows for just a bit of said flex. However, I did find that the aluminum plate was still a great typing experience. For reference, FR4 is a type of material that is mainly used as the primary material of PCBs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used O-rings in between the keyboard and the plate as a modification. Such a modification is known as a “burger-mount”, and is quite prevalent across many types of mounting types of boards, but especially in top mount boards. The intention is for the O-rings to act as a sort of gasket to lessen the harshness of the typing experience as opposed to the keyboard plate directly screwed into the board. In my experience, I think that the O-rings did make a noticeable difference in typing. I felt that the typing experience was a bit more bouncier as opposed to without it, especially with linear switches in the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designbuild-quality&quot;&gt;Design/Build Quality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected from a such a famed designer in the keyboard community as Ai03, I found the design of the keyboard (almost) impeccable and the build quality superb. This was an A stock keyboard, and it met that expectation perfectly (aside from the stripped screw issues…). The anodization of the color seemed as good as it could be, with it being a very dark gray, but not black. As for the design, I think Ai03 did a great job of everything. The keyboard looks especially clean with the symmetric design for both the left and right side, and it looks great with any keycap set I throw at it. But I would have preferred for an exterior brass weight as opposed to an inner one. Quite the nitpicking, but that’s just my preference. Otherwise, this board is quite the professional looking keyboard, and I think it looks great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-typing-experiencesound&quot;&gt;The typing experience/Sound&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started talking about the typing experience when I talked about O-rings, and to build up on that, I feel like the Meridian is an extremely solid typing experience. Aside from what I’ve already said, the ergonomic layout, while may look daunting to try to type on at first, comes naturally if you’re used to a normal QWERTY keyboard. It took me very little time to figure out how to type in this new layout. In fact, it felt very natural to switch to the Meridian, with little to no time needed to get used to it. I also found the bending angle and the split of the keyboard layout to be quite effective. I found that I was moving my hands less in long typing sessions (like the one I’m in this moment), and the angle very accommodating and comfortable to type on. I didn’t really miss the arrow keys either, as I am quite used to an arrowless 60% layout, and am quite accustomed to using separate layers for the arrows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the sound of the board, I found it surprisingly hollow stock, and I thought there could be some improvement. With the modifications I did above, the board sounded much fuller. Aside from the hollowness issues, I think the board sounds as good as a top mount board would. Obviously the switches would make the difference here on how they sound, but I do think that the Meridian lets the switches take center stage. For my tactile switches, it allows for quite the loud clacky typing sound that tactiles are known for, and for the linears, a very deep sound is achievable, depending on what switches you are using. Overall, I have no qualms with the sound signature of the Meridian. Here are some sound tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the price of $365 for the first round, I think that the keyboard is well worth the money that I paid for it. Is it expensive for a keyboard? Yes. Is it expensive for a custom mechanical keyboard of this quality? I’d say not really. There are a lot of other boards that are similar to this price or even more expensive for a 60% ergonomic. With the board not being a group buy, being sold in-stock, and continuously restocked for the foreseeable future, I think the Meridian is a great option if someone is looking for a custom ergonomic keyboard, especially if you don’t mind losing dedicated arrow keys in your workflow. I think I will be using the Meridian for any type of long form typing, as it feels great and less fatiguing to type when the hands aren’t moving as much around the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html">It’s been a while since I’ve actually built a keyboard. The last one that I did with soldering was the old HHKB style keyboard that I wrote about here that I built back in August. But now, I got a new board to build, and it’s actually my first keyboard that I would call high end. Enter the Meridian. Introduction to the Meridian The Meridian is a 60%, top-mount, ergonomic keyboard, designed by famed keyboard designer Ai03 in collaboration with a keyboard vendor, Prime Keyboards. It’s primarily based on the Prime E, a 40% ergonomic keyboard layout that was designed by Prime Keyboards, but in a 60% format. The design is basically a keyboard that is split in the middle for each hand, with the keys slightly angled for a more comfortable typing experience. The angle for the Meridian is a less aggressive 8 degrees, compared to the 12 degree angle bend that is common with other ergonomic boards, such as the Alice layout. With this layout of keys, the Meridian is an aluminium enclosure with a brass weight inside, and comes with an aluminium plate and a PCB. I got my Meridian in the first round, with a dark gray color option. The Meridian is going to be continuously offered in in-stock drops, but I was lucky enough to get it in the first drop. Getting it shipped here was somewhat of a nightmare, as the keyboard conveniently got caught in the middle of a blizzard. But I was able to thankfully get it here in one place without too many issues outside of little shipping delays. The building experience The building experience was mostly great and straightforward, except for a few issues that I ran into that was probably only in my unit. The main issue I found was the screws. The screws that came with the keyboard were Allen key screws, which was somewhat of an issue as my screwdriver didn’t work very well with the screws. I did have the right Allen screw bit, but the screws were screwed in quite tight by default. One screw in particular was stripped quite badly. So bad in fact, that the threads were stripped and in trying to remove it, I also stripped the head of the screw in the process. With the screw hole being recessed and inaccessible with pliers, and without other equipment to get the screw out, I had to uncomfortably use some elbow grease to… Let’s not get into the violent details, shall we? The point is, I had a very hard time with that one screw, and ended up with a very scuffed case at the end. Thankfully, it isn’t visible during normal use, and that’s good enough for me. Another issue came with my choice to do something called “mill-maxing” my keyboard PCB. This job is to solder on something called Mill-Max sockets into the holes of the PCBs to convert the PCB for hotswapping. There are many reasons why one would want to do this, the largest reason being the flexibility that a hotswappable keyboard gives. The actual job of soldering a Mill-Max socket isn’t too hard. Just insert the sockets on the right side, secure the sockets with a piece of Kapton tape or a keyboard switch, flip the PCB over, and carefully solder the socket. However, one can easily mess up the soldering job and have solder get in the socket, rendering it useless. When this happens, one has to desolder the socket, which can be a challenge. I had quite the difficulty trying to desolder a socket, as the socket kept on getting stuck while I tried to push it out, as the solder cooled before I could push it out. Resoldering a new one also proved a challenge, as the hole still had remnants of solder left in the hole. I ended up heating up the socket with my iron while trying to push the socket in the hole, which barely worked at the end. Aside from these issues though, the build went without a hitch, and at the end, I had a perfectly functioning hotswappable Meridian ready to go. Modifications There wasn’t too much to modify with this keyboard, but I did add a bit of sound dampening material and replaced the default aluminium plate with a FR4 plate. I added the sound dampener as I thought that the Meridian sounded a bit too hollow stock. With the white felt material that I added, the Meridian sounded a lot better and the hollowness was greatly alleviated. I changed to a FR4 plate as well, as I prefer a bit of flex with my typing experience, and the FR4 material allows for just a bit of said flex. However, I did find that the aluminum plate was still a great typing experience. For reference, FR4 is a type of material that is mainly used as the primary material of PCBs. I also used O-rings in between the keyboard and the plate as a modification. Such a modification is known as a “burger-mount”, and is quite prevalent across many types of mounting types of boards, but especially in top mount boards. The intention is for the O-rings to act as a sort of gasket to lessen the harshness of the typing experience as opposed to the keyboard plate directly screwed into the board. In my experience, I think that the O-rings did make a noticeable difference in typing. I felt that the typing experience was a bit more bouncier as opposed to without it, especially with linear switches in the keyboard. Design/Build Quality As expected from a such a famed designer in the keyboard community as Ai03, I found the design of the keyboard (almost) impeccable and the build quality superb. This was an A stock keyboard, and it met that expectation perfectly (aside from the stripped screw issues…). The anodization of the color seemed as good as it could be, with it being a very dark gray, but not black. As for the design, I think Ai03 did a great job of everything. The keyboard looks especially clean with the symmetric design for both the left and right side, and it looks great with any keycap set I throw at it. But I would have preferred for an exterior brass weight as opposed to an inner one. Quite the nitpicking, but that’s just my preference. Otherwise, this board is quite the professional looking keyboard, and I think it looks great. The typing experience/Sound I started talking about the typing experience when I talked about O-rings, and to build up on that, I feel like the Meridian is an extremely solid typing experience. Aside from what I’ve already said, the ergonomic layout, while may look daunting to try to type on at first, comes naturally if you’re used to a normal QWERTY keyboard. It took me very little time to figure out how to type in this new layout. In fact, it felt very natural to switch to the Meridian, with little to no time needed to get used to it. I also found the bending angle and the split of the keyboard layout to be quite effective. I found that I was moving my hands less in long typing sessions (like the one I’m in this moment), and the angle very accommodating and comfortable to type on. I didn’t really miss the arrow keys either, as I am quite used to an arrowless 60% layout, and am quite accustomed to using separate layers for the arrows. As for the sound of the board, I found it surprisingly hollow stock, and I thought there could be some improvement. With the modifications I did above, the board sounded much fuller. Aside from the hollowness issues, I think the board sounds as good as a top mount board would. Obviously the switches would make the difference here on how they sound, but I do think that the Meridian lets the switches take center stage. For my tactile switches, it allows for quite the loud clacky typing sound that tactiles are known for, and for the linears, a very deep sound is achievable, depending on what switches you are using. Overall, I have no qualms with the sound signature of the Meridian. Here are some sound tests. Conclusion At the price of $365 for the first round, I think that the keyboard is well worth the money that I paid for it. Is it expensive for a keyboard? Yes. Is it expensive for a custom mechanical keyboard of this quality? I’d say not really. There are a lot of other boards that are similar to this price or even more expensive for a 60% ergonomic. With the board not being a group buy, being sold in-stock, and continuously restocked for the foreseeable future, I think the Meridian is a great option if someone is looking for a custom ergonomic keyboard, especially if you don’t mind losing dedicated arrow keys in your workflow. I think I will be using the Meridian for any type of long form typing, as it feels great and less fatiguing to type when the hands aren’t moving as much around the keyboard.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Horse60 custom mechanical keyboard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/02/04/Horse60-Build.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Horse60 custom mechanical keyboard" /><published>2021-02-04T10:30:23+09:00</published><updated>2021-02-04T10:30:23+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/02/04/Horse60%20Build</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2021/02/04/Horse60-Build.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I started writing this blogpost about the end of summer of 2020, but for one reason or another, never got around to actually finishing it. It’s been quite a while since I’ve actually built this board, but I still wanted to write a piece on it. I think I’ll just treat this post as a very long retrospective. Anyways, enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-02-04horse60/20210119_140312.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Completed Build&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, some more exciting stuff to write about. More keyboard content, but this time, even more custom. After 2 months of planning and waiting for shipments, I’ve got my new keyboard. This time, with even more custom parts and soldering. Every and all mods that I could think of to make this board feel and sound the best at its price point was done, and I think it came out fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, off to the blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theme-of-the-build-trying-new-stuff&quot;&gt;Theme of the build: Trying new stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire concept of building this keyboard was based on wanting to try something new for once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my time in the mechanical keyboard hobby, I’ve only tried using tactile and clicky switches. For this build, I wanted to try a different type of switch that I haven’t thought of using before. So, I went on the hunt for linear switches, the type of switches that I’ve never tried. After a lot of research, I decided to go with the C3 Equalz Tangerine switches, known to be some of the smoothest linear switches around. Well, they’re just really a recolor of a prominant linear switch from the manufacturer JWK, but that’s beside the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also wanted to try a new form factor. I’ve always thought I needed arrow keys on my board, so 65% was the smallest I could go. So for this build, I thought to go for a 60% form factor, but I decided to take it a step further and go with a HHKB form factor. This form factor is a symmetrical design with the bottom row removing the left and right control keys. Getting used to the split spacebar and the Control key where once the Caps Lock is will take some time to get used to, but I think it’ll work out to something great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard plate material and mounting system is also something that I was looking to experiment with. The most conventional plate material seems to be aluminium, and the most widly used mounting system seems to be either tray mount or integrated mount. I’ve used all of these kinds of plates and mounting methods, but wanted to try something different. So for this build, I decided to use FR4, the material used for PCBs, as the plate material. I also decided to go with the top mounting method, complete with O-rings to act as a form of a gasket in between the screws holding the case, PCB, and plate together. The case that I went with came with a stainless steel plate, and there were no plate files that I could use to get my own cut. So, I decided to pull out the calipers, and make the files on my own. Here’s the result of the FR4 plate that I made:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-02-04horse60/20210204_123845.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FR4 plate.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HorseyMask/keebplates/blob/main/xd64%20plate%20v1.dxf&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to the files if you so wish to make your own plates. The keyboard case is the HHKB case from KPRepublic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the work of actually soldering to put the keyboard together was something new to me. I previously didn’t want to go with soldering my keyboards because I felt that I wanted the freedom to change out my switches easily on the same board. Soldering itself was also a bit of an extra step that I was somewhat scared of to get into. But I always wanted to try soldering as a new skill to have in my repertoire. So for this build, I decided to take the jump and go for it and learn to solder with this build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this involve trying something new, and I think it paid off.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-02-04horse60/20210131_112307.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished build, without keycaps.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-experience-of-using-the-board&quot;&gt;The experience of using the board&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the exterior of the build. For how cheap the KPRepublic case is, I think it look great. While there are some imperfections, such as the HHKB blockers being slightly too small, I think it is a great case for the price. An HHKB case with mostly proper blockers and top mount, for less than $90 is quite the killer price. There is some backlight lighting under the board on the PCB, but I didnt mind those too much, as I don’t care too much about RGB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to the elephant in the room: the actual typing experience. I didn’t know what to expect before I started typing on the board. There it was, a keyboard so wildly different than what I was used to. Different keyboard form fact, different style of switches, and different mounting design. What I did expect was a better typing experience than my previous boards of tray and integrated plate mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I was right. The top mount really helped with making the typing experience feel more consistant across the board (pun somewhat intended). The FR4 plate material also did a great job for a bit more flex in the typing experience, as with the O-rings that were used. All this combined made for quite a consistant typing experience with a lot more flex. I was also very surprised as to how much I liked linears. I was always very partial to tactiles, and scoffed at using linears. Well, with the combination of this board and a premium linear switch… I think I’m sold on linear switches. Or at least, I can properly appreciate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the sound, the board itself sounds a lot better than I expected. For the price, the acoustics are pretty good, and I do think the foam that I also put in the board is helping with the sound. The keycaps that I’m using with the keyboard also are probably contributing to the sound. The KAT profile that the Milkshakes are using sound quite good and give a more deeper sound signature in my opinion. Speaking of pitch, the Tangerine switches are no deep sounding switch. In fact, they’re quite high pitched. This part of the Tangerine switches is a bit of a letdown for myself, as I think I prefer a more deeper sound for my keyboards. But overall, I think the keyboard sound pretty great. Here’s a sound test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/assets/audio/2021-02-04horse60/untitled.wav&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I do love how the entire build came around at the end, espically with the money I paid for everything. While there are a few rough areas that can be identified, most of the build came out as well as I would like it to be. Espically with a lot of stuff being made by myself, such as the plate files to make the new FR4 plate made this quite the rewarding experience at the end. I also came out with the build learning a lot of new things, such as that I can like linear switches, and also a plethora of knowledge involving the construction of a keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retrospective-of-the-build-around-half-a-year-in&quot;&gt;Retrospective of the build around half a year in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All right, back to Feburary me. I’m finishing up the writing of this blog entry after quite a lot time due to my own lazyness, but I’ll take this as a chance to give my thoughts on the entire build after around half a year’s usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still love using the board, for all the reasons stated above. I think that it is really a showing of how much you can get for so little in the custom side. While obviously there is quite the price tag for going custom for mechcanical keyboards, the price is still quite managagable for it being custom, espically for the keyboard being top mounted. As for some dislikes from the board that came from using it, the high pitched sound profile of the Tangerines have been a bit draining, even though I have mostly gotten used to it. Also, the low angle of the case also can be an issue for comfortable typing, but it isnt too bad. Just a little nitpicking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2021-02-04horse60/20210204_123818.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Another keyboard shot in direct sunlight.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I’ll close out this project and move on to other ones in the keyboard area. I got another good build coming up, and I’ll definitely try to get a blogpost up for that one too, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html">I started writing this blogpost about the end of summer of 2020, but for one reason or another, never got around to actually finishing it. It’s been quite a while since I’ve actually built this board, but I still wanted to write a piece on it. I think I’ll just treat this post as a very long retrospective. Anyways, enjoy! Pictures first. Finally, some more exciting stuff to write about. More keyboard content, but this time, even more custom. After 2 months of planning and waiting for shipments, I’ve got my new keyboard. This time, with even more custom parts and soldering. Every and all mods that I could think of to make this board feel and sound the best at its price point was done, and I think it came out fantastic. With that said, off to the blogpost. Theme of the build: Trying new stuff The entire concept of building this keyboard was based on wanting to try something new for once. In my time in the mechanical keyboard hobby, I’ve only tried using tactile and clicky switches. For this build, I wanted to try a different type of switch that I haven’t thought of using before. So, I went on the hunt for linear switches, the type of switches that I’ve never tried. After a lot of research, I decided to go with the C3 Equalz Tangerine switches, known to be some of the smoothest linear switches around. Well, they’re just really a recolor of a prominant linear switch from the manufacturer JWK, but that’s beside the point. I’ve also wanted to try a new form factor. I’ve always thought I needed arrow keys on my board, so 65% was the smallest I could go. So for this build, I thought to go for a 60% form factor, but I decided to take it a step further and go with a HHKB form factor. This form factor is a symmetrical design with the bottom row removing the left and right control keys. Getting used to the split spacebar and the Control key where once the Caps Lock is will take some time to get used to, but I think it’ll work out to something great. The keyboard plate material and mounting system is also something that I was looking to experiment with. The most conventional plate material seems to be aluminium, and the most widly used mounting system seems to be either tray mount or integrated mount. I’ve used all of these kinds of plates and mounting methods, but wanted to try something different. So for this build, I decided to use FR4, the material used for PCBs, as the plate material. I also decided to go with the top mounting method, complete with O-rings to act as a form of a gasket in between the screws holding the case, PCB, and plate together. The case that I went with came with a stainless steel plate, and there were no plate files that I could use to get my own cut. So, I decided to pull out the calipers, and make the files on my own. Here’s the result of the FR4 plate that I made: Here’s a link to the files if you so wish to make your own plates. The keyboard case is the HHKB case from KPRepublic. Finally, the work of actually soldering to put the keyboard together was something new to me. I previously didn’t want to go with soldering my keyboards because I felt that I wanted the freedom to change out my switches easily on the same board. Soldering itself was also a bit of an extra step that I was somewhat scared of to get into. But I always wanted to try soldering as a new skill to have in my repertoire. So for this build, I decided to take the jump and go for it and learn to solder with this build. All of this involve trying something new, and I think it paid off. The experience of using the board First, the exterior of the build. For how cheap the KPRepublic case is, I think it look great. While there are some imperfections, such as the HHKB blockers being slightly too small, I think it is a great case for the price. An HHKB case with mostly proper blockers and top mount, for less than $90 is quite the killer price. There is some backlight lighting under the board on the PCB, but I didnt mind those too much, as I don’t care too much about RGB. Now, to the elephant in the room: the actual typing experience. I didn’t know what to expect before I started typing on the board. There it was, a keyboard so wildly different than what I was used to. Different keyboard form fact, different style of switches, and different mounting design. What I did expect was a better typing experience than my previous boards of tray and integrated plate mount. And I was right. The top mount really helped with making the typing experience feel more consistant across the board (pun somewhat intended). The FR4 plate material also did a great job for a bit more flex in the typing experience, as with the O-rings that were used. All this combined made for quite a consistant typing experience with a lot more flex. I was also very surprised as to how much I liked linears. I was always very partial to tactiles, and scoffed at using linears. Well, with the combination of this board and a premium linear switch… I think I’m sold on linear switches. Or at least, I can properly appreciate them. As for the sound, the board itself sounds a lot better than I expected. For the price, the acoustics are pretty good, and I do think the foam that I also put in the board is helping with the sound. The keycaps that I’m using with the keyboard also are probably contributing to the sound. The KAT profile that the Milkshakes are using sound quite good and give a more deeper sound signature in my opinion. Speaking of pitch, the Tangerine switches are no deep sounding switch. In fact, they’re quite high pitched. This part of the Tangerine switches is a bit of a letdown for myself, as I think I prefer a more deeper sound for my keyboards. But overall, I think the keyboard sound pretty great. Here’s a sound test: /assets/audio/2021-02-04horse60/untitled.wav Overall, I do love how the entire build came around at the end, espically with the money I paid for everything. While there are a few rough areas that can be identified, most of the build came out as well as I would like it to be. Espically with a lot of stuff being made by myself, such as the plate files to make the new FR4 plate made this quite the rewarding experience at the end. I also came out with the build learning a lot of new things, such as that I can like linear switches, and also a plethora of knowledge involving the construction of a keyboard. Retrospective of the build around half a year in All right, back to Feburary me. I’m finishing up the writing of this blog entry after quite a lot time due to my own lazyness, but I’ll take this as a chance to give my thoughts on the entire build after around half a year’s usage. I still love using the board, for all the reasons stated above. I think that it is really a showing of how much you can get for so little in the custom side. While obviously there is quite the price tag for going custom for mechcanical keyboards, the price is still quite managagable for it being custom, espically for the keyboard being top mounted. As for some dislikes from the board that came from using it, the high pitched sound profile of the Tangerines have been a bit draining, even though I have mostly gotten used to it. Also, the low angle of the case also can be an issue for comfortable typing, but it isnt too bad. Just a little nitpicking. With that, I’ll close out this project and move on to other ones in the keyboard area. I got another good build coming up, and I’ll definitely try to get a blogpost up for that one too, so stay tuned.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of year review - 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2021/01/15/End-of-year-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of year review - 2020" /><published>2021-01-15T14:12:00+09:00</published><updated>2021-01-15T14:12:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2021/01/15/End%20of%20year%20review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2021/01/15/End-of-year-review.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;well&quot;&gt;Well….&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a year was 2020. Looking back at the 2019 year of review that I wrote a bit longer than a year ago, I envy my end of 2019 myself for being so… ignorant and not knowing the whirlwind that 2020 brought. Regardless, 2020 was obivously not a normal year at all, and I probably don’t need to explain why. Instead of focusing on those past events though, I prefer to not talk about those events in the past, and leave those behind, and move on with the future. I don’t expect 2021 to be the 180 degree flip of 2020, but I hope things are much better this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-void-of-emptiness-of-posts&quot;&gt;The void of emptiness of posts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the blog in the year of 2020, after May with the Keychron post, everything kind of just falls off a cliff. Looking back on it, from then forward wasn’t really a great time, and I think the quarantine part of 2020 got the best of me. Espically from the 2nd semester of sophomore year, things really looked down for me, and I was quite in the unmotivated rut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mixture of being tired of not being able to meet friends and online classes being hard to focus on made me extremely listless and apathetic. This naturally extended to my hobbies and of course, this blog. But seeing that I’m writing for this blog again, I still remember that it exists. Anyways, that’s the explanation for the giant gap of activity here, as well as a little looking back at how this year went for myself. Hopefully this year will bring me more motivation for more exciting projects and work. That is what I would say, if it wasnt for…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;military-the-looming-threat&quot;&gt;Military: the looming threat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Korean male national, its bound to happen. Every male Korean that isn’t unhealthy over the age of 18 is required to perform military service, and I’m no exception. As soon as I leave the hornet’s nest that is 2020, 2021 approaches me with another challenge that I frankly, never asked for. Naturally, this cuts into all my hobbies, as well as the projects that I would like to do. But it’s (mostly) unavoidable, and I have to figure out how to get through it as painless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This naturally leads into my first goal for the year: to maintain my health as best as possible. The ultimate reason for this is to ensure that I enter military as physically fit as possible, so I dont succumb to some really terrible pain during basic boot camp and beyond. This goal is proving to be quite the challenge, as I cannot go to a gym right now due to COVID restrictions, but I am trying my best with dumbbells I have at home and using the outside for cardio exercise. I hope that I can get my body to the point where I can withstand at least some of the physically stressing environments of Military.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-hobby-rekindled-keyboards&quot;&gt;A hobby rekindled: Keyboards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything positive about 2020 came around, it was that my interest in keyboards grew exponetially. While I was also interested in mechanical keyboards, particularly custom keyboard switches, the last year has brought around a great change in my keyboard interests. I started joining group buys for keycaps and keyboards, interacted with many people and vendors about keyboard related stuff and news, and experimented with various keyboard parts. It really became an enjoyable hobby to look at, and it was basically one of the more brigther beacons in the dark 2020 that I was forced to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this event in 2020, another goal for myself in 2020 was to try to contribute to the world of mechanical keyboards more than before. Whether that is in the form of programming new firmware for a keyboard that I am using, to designing stuff related to keyboards that I wanted to share, I want to do anything that can help someone else in the hobby. With the limited time that I have this year with military looming in constantly as a real responsibility that I need to take care of, I want to do this in them most meaningful way I can with the time I have left as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;something-new-a-proper-job&quot;&gt;Something new: a proper job&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new thing that I want to try going for this year, while I still have the time before military, is to finally try to get a job and work in society. While that may seem like a tall task in the job market for 2021, I just want to try to find a job that will give me some sort of experience in just working. With military coming up, and my disdain for online classes for university growing, I just decided to take a leave of absence. With this leave of absence, I want to get a job to see how it feels like to work in society while being out of education for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-return-to-an-old-hobby-drawing&quot;&gt;A return to an old hobby: drawing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a new hobby came to me with keyboards, another one left, in an unwilling way. That hobby was drawing, which i picked up in 2019 and continued throughout the first half of 2020. But with the great listlessness and apathy that occured with the latter part of 2020 that I talked about before, so did the hobby of drawing. Inbetween the motivation that was shot now due to the depression then, I feel like the lack of a social aspect of drawing also kept me out. In school, I was surrounded by many people that were drawing in the club I was in, and I wanted to follow suit as well. But with 2020 and the lack of social activities, those social opportunities died out, and so did my love to improve my craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the final goal that I have, I want to at least get back into the drawing hobby in some fashion. I feel like I have abandoned it unconsciously with all the issues I faced in the latter part of 2020, and I want to revive it and work on it as much as possible. I do have some fear that I won’t be able to draw as well as I used to before I slowly stopped, and I do think that it is the main force driving me away from reaching for the drawing tablet. But I do really want to try to get back to it, regardless of the fears that I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yearly-theme-the-year-of-preperation&quot;&gt;Yearly theme: The year of preperation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CGP Gray, a Youtuber I follow, was pushing the idea of yearly themes, a guide towards the new year that you face. I decided to follow suit, and make this year, the year of preperation. This year will be largely dominanted with me facing an unavoidable task that is the military. For this, I wish this year to be a year where I make all the preperations I can to make the transition to military as painless as possible. I also want this year to be as fufilling as possible before I enter the military so that I can enter without any regret that I was wasting my time before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was quite the personal post, but I feel like it had to be made, with this year being such a pivotal year for myself. Hopefully it was worth writing and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Well…. What a year was 2020. Looking back at the 2019 year of review that I wrote a bit longer than a year ago, I envy my end of 2019 myself for being so… ignorant and not knowing the whirlwind that 2020 brought. Regardless, 2020 was obivously not a normal year at all, and I probably don’t need to explain why. Instead of focusing on those past events though, I prefer to not talk about those events in the past, and leave those behind, and move on with the future. I don’t expect 2021 to be the 180 degree flip of 2020, but I hope things are much better this year. The void of emptiness of posts Looking at the blog in the year of 2020, after May with the Keychron post, everything kind of just falls off a cliff. Looking back on it, from then forward wasn’t really a great time, and I think the quarantine part of 2020 got the best of me. Espically from the 2nd semester of sophomore year, things really looked down for me, and I was quite in the unmotivated rut. A mixture of being tired of not being able to meet friends and online classes being hard to focus on made me extremely listless and apathetic. This naturally extended to my hobbies and of course, this blog. But seeing that I’m writing for this blog again, I still remember that it exists. Anyways, that’s the explanation for the giant gap of activity here, as well as a little looking back at how this year went for myself. Hopefully this year will bring me more motivation for more exciting projects and work. That is what I would say, if it wasnt for… Military: the looming threat As a Korean male national, its bound to happen. Every male Korean that isn’t unhealthy over the age of 18 is required to perform military service, and I’m no exception. As soon as I leave the hornet’s nest that is 2020, 2021 approaches me with another challenge that I frankly, never asked for. Naturally, this cuts into all my hobbies, as well as the projects that I would like to do. But it’s (mostly) unavoidable, and I have to figure out how to get through it as painless as possible. This naturally leads into my first goal for the year: to maintain my health as best as possible. The ultimate reason for this is to ensure that I enter military as physically fit as possible, so I dont succumb to some really terrible pain during basic boot camp and beyond. This goal is proving to be quite the challenge, as I cannot go to a gym right now due to COVID restrictions, but I am trying my best with dumbbells I have at home and using the outside for cardio exercise. I hope that I can get my body to the point where I can withstand at least some of the physically stressing environments of Military. A hobby rekindled: Keyboards If anything positive about 2020 came around, it was that my interest in keyboards grew exponetially. While I was also interested in mechanical keyboards, particularly custom keyboard switches, the last year has brought around a great change in my keyboard interests. I started joining group buys for keycaps and keyboards, interacted with many people and vendors about keyboard related stuff and news, and experimented with various keyboard parts. It really became an enjoyable hobby to look at, and it was basically one of the more brigther beacons in the dark 2020 that I was forced to go through. With this event in 2020, another goal for myself in 2020 was to try to contribute to the world of mechanical keyboards more than before. Whether that is in the form of programming new firmware for a keyboard that I am using, to designing stuff related to keyboards that I wanted to share, I want to do anything that can help someone else in the hobby. With the limited time that I have this year with military looming in constantly as a real responsibility that I need to take care of, I want to do this in them most meaningful way I can with the time I have left as well. Something new: a proper job A new thing that I want to try going for this year, while I still have the time before military, is to finally try to get a job and work in society. While that may seem like a tall task in the job market for 2021, I just want to try to find a job that will give me some sort of experience in just working. With military coming up, and my disdain for online classes for university growing, I just decided to take a leave of absence. With this leave of absence, I want to get a job to see how it feels like to work in society while being out of education for a while. A return to an old hobby: drawing While a new hobby came to me with keyboards, another one left, in an unwilling way. That hobby was drawing, which i picked up in 2019 and continued throughout the first half of 2020. But with the great listlessness and apathy that occured with the latter part of 2020 that I talked about before, so did the hobby of drawing. Inbetween the motivation that was shot now due to the depression then, I feel like the lack of a social aspect of drawing also kept me out. In school, I was surrounded by many people that were drawing in the club I was in, and I wanted to follow suit as well. But with 2020 and the lack of social activities, those social opportunities died out, and so did my love to improve my craft. So, for the final goal that I have, I want to at least get back into the drawing hobby in some fashion. I feel like I have abandoned it unconsciously with all the issues I faced in the latter part of 2020, and I want to revive it and work on it as much as possible. I do have some fear that I won’t be able to draw as well as I used to before I slowly stopped, and I do think that it is the main force driving me away from reaching for the drawing tablet. But I do really want to try to get back to it, regardless of the fears that I have. Yearly theme: The year of preperation CGP Gray, a Youtuber I follow, was pushing the idea of yearly themes, a guide towards the new year that you face. I decided to follow suit, and make this year, the year of preperation. This year will be largely dominanted with me facing an unavoidable task that is the military. For this, I wish this year to be a year where I make all the preperations I can to make the transition to military as painless as possible. I also want this year to be as fufilling as possible before I enter the military so that I can enter without any regret that I was wasting my time before. This was quite the personal post, but I feel like it had to be made, with this year being such a pivotal year for myself. Hopefully it was worth writing and sharing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keychron K6 mod log/ review - Lots of features with price cuts.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2020/05/04/Keychron-K6-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keychron K6 mod log/ review - Lots of features with price cuts." /><published>2020-05-04T10:30:23+09:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T10:30:23+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2020/05/04/Keychron%20K6%20review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2020/05/04/Keychron-K6-review.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-05-04keychron/20200504_113141.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unboxing.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full image gallery &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/FwzIoRr&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wrote anything for this blog, but I’ve finally got something that I want to write about, and was pretty excited for. And that is the Keychron K6, a 65% mechanical keyboard with features such as backlighting, hotswappability, and the big one, Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, the big one is that it has both hotswappability and Bluetooth connectivity on the same board. But anyways, that’s for the review. Let’s get on to the buildlog first before I get into the review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mod-log&quot;&gt;Mod log&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL:DR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used 67g Zilent v2 switches. Get plate mount stabs and don’t be dumb like me. Have a separate switch remover in handy. Lots of empty space in chassis, get your sound dampening foam ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the initial unboxing and being done with checking out the keyboard, I got to work first by removing the switches that were installed by default. I found the switches on this board to be much easier to remove with a switch remover than my other hotswap board, the Drop ALT keyboard. I am guessing that it’s due to either different hotswap sockets, or the switch on the Drop ALT board (Halo Clears for me) just being harder to remove. Might just be my board.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-05-04keychron/20200504_121200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Removing switches.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a notice that the included switch remover, in my experience, is garbage. It’s not big enough to comfortably remove the switches at all. I tried using it for one switch, and immediately switched to the one that came with the ALT to remove the switches here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this process, I unscrewed the plate of the board to remove the plate and the PCB at the same time. All I needed to do was unscrew the 6 screws on top of the plate, and I was able to easily remove the PCB/plate. It seemed like they are a combined unit, as they popped off together. This revealed the battery for the keyboard at the bottom, along with the bottom of the case. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-05-04keychron/20200504_122602.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opened up.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case was filled with a ton of empty space, so I got to work with the sound dampening foam I had on hand. This is just to reduce potential ping and hollow typing sounds due to the emptiness of the case. This was relatively simple, as all I needed to do was cut the foam into smaller sizes to fit the little sections that the bottom was divided in. I also needed to cut holes for some of the foam, due to the screw holes for the keyboard. This took a lot less time than the Drop ALT, where I literally cut a single large piece of foam with holes for each key and put that on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I screwed the PCB and the plate back on, and worked on the stabilizers next. The ones that came with the board were acceptable. The space bar stabilizer was factory lubed as well. But they didn’t sound as well I wanted, so I got to work. I actually bought some genuine GMK stabilizers in preparation for this project, but I realized I got the wrong stabilizers. Get plate mount stabilizers if you are looking to buy this board and replace stabilizers. I bought PCB snap in stabilizers, and I realized I made a huge mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of waiting another week or two for stabilizer delivery, I just removed the wire and the insert parts of the genuine stabilizers, and just used the stock included mounting parts for a makeshift pseudo-genuine stabilizer. This seemed to work pretty well, and I don’t know how much of a difference this is from a completely genuine stabilizer is, but I made with what I had. With this, I did the usual clipping and lubing mods and put them in the board. Personally, I think they sound good enough, or as good as it gets for this board at least.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-05-04keychron/20200504_141751.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Almost done.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I inserted the switches of my choice. I made the choice for 67g Zilent v2s that I had on hand, the reasons that’ll be made clear in the review. I had these switches before in the ALT, until I made myself some Holy Pandas, so I had already lubed all the switches I needed. (Thankfully.) These popped in the hotswap sockets easily, making this part pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, I would like to add that these Zilent switches do not seem to be optimal for hotswap boards, as they do not securely hold on into the hotswap sockets. While they are firm enough for daily use, when you try to remove the keycap, the switch often pops right off of the socket along with the keycap. I don’t know if this is the switch’s fault, or the socket, or even the keycap, but just a warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-05-04keychron/20200504_211809.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Glamor shot.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
With that, and putting back the keycaps on the keyboard, I finished up the modding process for this board. This board was relatively a breeze to work on, as there were very little fiddely parts to work with with disassembly. I thought that the battery in the base might be a pain to work around, but as long I was careful with the cable attaching the battery to the PCB, it was fine. Just remember to purchase the right stabilizers to avoid the issue I had in this mod log.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr-1&quot;&gt;TLDR:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️65% Hotswap + Bluetooth killer combo, if you’re lazy and want a BT mech keeb with custom switches without soldering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️Good compatibility with wide variety of systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️Suprisingly decent acoustics (with modding with sound dampening foam and lubing)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️Good price value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;❌Typing experience would be good if it wasn’t for cheap keycaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;❌No easy customization or QMK. Some software promised in future, but unknown for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;❌Somewhat weird layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall best suited as a first 65% mech keyboard, secondary mobile keyboard, or a keyboard if you have a good keycap set to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prelude&quot;&gt;Prelude&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I talk about the keyboard, I want to talk briefly about the switches that came with the board. I ordered a board with Gateron Brown switches, mostly due to curiosity on how they felt to type on, and also because I love tactile switches and wanted to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short conclusion here is that Holy Pandas and ZealPC switches have ruined me, and these didn’t feel that tactile. Maybe a bit more tactile than Cherry Browns, but still not that great. Also, the switches felt too light for me, as I’m now used to 67g springs for my switches. Overall, not that great of an experience, but I was going to swap them out anyways, so I had no issue. I think if you just wanted a cheap entry into tactile switches without going all in, these would be fine though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the elephant of the room that is the board itself, I feel like overall, the Keychron K6 is an excellent keyboard for the price (especially at the Kickstarter price) with a combination of features that aren’t seen a lot in other boards. But there are a few glaring issues that sadly do bring it down a bit that I’ll get to in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-positives&quot;&gt;The positives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest focus that I had when buying this specific board was the combination of two features that I just couldn’t find anywhere else: hotswappability and Bluetooth. Every other board out their has either hotswap sockets or Bluetooth. No other board in the 65% range that I could find had both of these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was I looking for both Bluetooth and hotswapping though? Well, I was looking for a secondary keyboard to bring along wherever I go so I don’t need to type on mush wherever I go. For that, I found that Bluetooth is actually a killer feature, as going wireless on the go makes great sense, and allows me to use the keyboard with an iPad as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also wanted to use the Zilents to get a tactile experience but silent enough to use in a public space. I could have gone for a soldering job with a 65% kit that supported Bluetooth, but I wanted more freedom of choice and ease of use, so I looked for a hotswap board as well. This led me on a search for a 65%, hotswap Bluetooth keyboard that was fruitless until the Keychron K6 came around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, how are the Bluetooth features? Well, I typed the entirety of the mod long part on my iPad with the Bluetooth feature on, and I’m happy to say it was a pretty decent experience. I had no issues typing everything up, and didn’t have much issues with latency as well. That was just for normal word processing work though. I wouldn’t really recommend just using this as a wireless gaming keyboard though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Bluetooth 3.0, Keychron claims that you can connect up to three devices with up to 72 hours for the RGB version, and 68 for the white backlight version. While I haven’t used the K6 enough to benchmark those battery claims, the claimed 4000mAH battery seems pretty large enough to step up to that task. Multi-device pairing also worked great, with the keyboard switching between my iPad and my Galaxy S9 via keyboard shortcuts seamlessly after the initial Bluetooth sync process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other features, the K6 also has different modes for Windows/Android and Mac/iOS, increasing the compatibility with the amount of devices you can use this with. The lighting is also good enough for normal backlight use. I purchased the white lighting, non-RGB version of the K6, and I’m finding the backlight adequate enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for acoustics, it was surprisingly decent. Through the sound dampening foam additions, as well as lubed stabilizers, I’m getting very little ping on the board. Not bad for a cheaper casing. With the combination of the Zilent v2 switches, I think this keyboard would be a great silent but tactile keyboard to use in public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there was the one thing I was worried about, it being the typing experience. I was worried about the height of the keyboard, as other Keychron keyboards were reported to be too high for comfortable types without a palm rest. But personally, I found it comfortable mostly, even for long-ish (30+ minutes) sessions of typing, without a palmrest or using a hovering technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I do see why some people wouldn’t like using this keyboard for long sessions, I was mostly fine. However, there is another aspect of the typing experience that I wasn’t so happy about…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-negatives&quot;&gt;The negatives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting straight back to the typing experience, the included keycaps are pretty meh to bad. I’m not usually very picky about my keycaps, as I used stock keycaps for every keyboard I’ve owned. But these keycaps may make me think differently this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the design is fine, with the subdued black keycaps with colored legends for the function keys and the orange highlight key for the lighting. These are extremely thin ABS keycaps however, that do feel somewhat cheap to type on. But the worst part about them, in my opinion, is the glossy and somewhat “sticky’ texture that they have. I don’t know if this will wear off as time goes on, but as of now, it really does lower the user experience a bit. Pretty mediocre, to even bad overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue is the lack of customizability and the nonstandard key layout. As of now, the K6 has no way first party way of customizing what your keyboard can do. No macros, switching key layouts, RGB/lighting customization features, nothing. You can use other software like Sharpkeys, as stated by Keychron, to remap some buttons, but that’s a pretty curveball way to solve the problem. Personally, I’m really missing a dedicated Delete key on my board, and would very much like to remap a key, like the light button, for Delete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that Keychron has promised customization software within the year for the K6, but that’s not a guarantee that I would bet on when making the purchase decision. And it’s no QMK, definitely. But hey, it’s got a lot of pretty lighting modes, right? right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonstandard layout is a smaller nitpick for me, but may not be for others, especially due to the quality of the keycaps. The K6 features two separate Function keys, which kind of makes finding a keycap set harder. Also, the bottom row is definitely nonstandard due to the Function keys as well. Though I am finding a lot of 65% boards to be nonstandard as well, so the K6 is not alone in this issue. But if you are shopping for a replacement keycap set for this board, it’s worth noting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’re some more questionable design choices that personally are little naggling issues that aren’t too problematic, but worth mentioning. The USB-C port on the left side is one, making normal USB-C cables more of a pain to use. At least they include a braided, L-style USB-C cable that works better for this configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large amount of empty space in the chassis is also a pointer of an odd design choice. Maybe it was for the battery, but that also doesn’t take too much space at all. It’s a weird choice that I needed to fix with foam to improve acoustics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the aluminum version of the keyboard just being aluminum bar slide-on additions to the plastic model makes the aluminum model not worth to get, in my opinion. If you’re paying extra for aluminum, I’d expect a full aluminum machined case, not just 4 aluminum bars. The plastic chassis is also just a very meh design, as you can clearly see cut corners where the aluminum bars would have been slid in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;price--conclusion&quot;&gt;Price / Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at both sides, I can attribute most of the cons of this device as probably cuts made to make the price as low as possible. The poor keycap quality, lack of customization or QMK, empty casing, and questionable aluminum version all seem to directly stem from price cuts. However, I don’t see that necessarily as a bad thing, and I see where the rest of the budget went into: hotswap and Bluetooth support, as well as wide device compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Keychron’s website, it’s currently $74 for a hotswap, white backlight version of the K6 (the one I got), excluding shipping, with the Kickstarter price trailing slightly behind at $69. I’d say if you’re looking for a 65% mechanical keyboard with a ton of core features for the cheap, the K6 is a pretty decent choice, especially if you already have a keycap set to use and don’t care too much about customization. I would find it harder to recommend if you are looking for more premium features like PBT caps and customization out of the box though. Don’t get the aluminum version though, it’s just not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d also recommend this board if you’re someone like me and looking for a secondary that you want as a portable keyboard to use for your laptop or iPad when you’re out. That way, you can always have the best typing experience anywhere, with the added benefit of Bluetooth as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m going to enjoy this board a lot outside of my desk. I’m just happy I got a Bluetooth 65% board for my Zilents. Now I just need to go waste even more money on PBT caps… But that’s a story for another time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html">Full image gallery here. It’s been a while since I wrote anything for this blog, but I’ve finally got something that I want to write about, and was pretty excited for. And that is the Keychron K6, a 65% mechanical keyboard with features such as backlighting, hotswappability, and the big one, Bluetooth. Actually, the big one is that it has both hotswappability and Bluetooth connectivity on the same board. But anyways, that’s for the review. Let’s get on to the buildlog first before I get into the review. Mod log TL:DR Used 67g Zilent v2 switches. Get plate mount stabs and don’t be dumb like me. Have a separate switch remover in handy. Lots of empty space in chassis, get your sound dampening foam ready. After the initial unboxing and being done with checking out the keyboard, I got to work first by removing the switches that were installed by default. I found the switches on this board to be much easier to remove with a switch remover than my other hotswap board, the Drop ALT keyboard. I am guessing that it’s due to either different hotswap sockets, or the switch on the Drop ALT board (Halo Clears for me) just being harder to remove. Might just be my board. Also, a notice that the included switch remover, in my experience, is garbage. It’s not big enough to comfortably remove the switches at all. I tried using it for one switch, and immediately switched to the one that came with the ALT to remove the switches here. After this process, I unscrewed the plate of the board to remove the plate and the PCB at the same time. All I needed to do was unscrew the 6 screws on top of the plate, and I was able to easily remove the PCB/plate. It seemed like they are a combined unit, as they popped off together. This revealed the battery for the keyboard at the bottom, along with the bottom of the case. The case was filled with a ton of empty space, so I got to work with the sound dampening foam I had on hand. This is just to reduce potential ping and hollow typing sounds due to the emptiness of the case. This was relatively simple, as all I needed to do was cut the foam into smaller sizes to fit the little sections that the bottom was divided in. I also needed to cut holes for some of the foam, due to the screw holes for the keyboard. This took a lot less time than the Drop ALT, where I literally cut a single large piece of foam with holes for each key and put that on. After that, I screwed the PCB and the plate back on, and worked on the stabilizers next. The ones that came with the board were acceptable. The space bar stabilizer was factory lubed as well. But they didn’t sound as well I wanted, so I got to work. I actually bought some genuine GMK stabilizers in preparation for this project, but I realized I got the wrong stabilizers. Get plate mount stabilizers if you are looking to buy this board and replace stabilizers. I bought PCB snap in stabilizers, and I realized I made a huge mistake. Instead of waiting another week or two for stabilizer delivery, I just removed the wire and the insert parts of the genuine stabilizers, and just used the stock included mounting parts for a makeshift pseudo-genuine stabilizer. This seemed to work pretty well, and I don’t know how much of a difference this is from a completely genuine stabilizer is, but I made with what I had. With this, I did the usual clipping and lubing mods and put them in the board. Personally, I think they sound good enough, or as good as it gets for this board at least. Finally, I inserted the switches of my choice. I made the choice for 67g Zilent v2s that I had on hand, the reasons that’ll be made clear in the review. I had these switches before in the ALT, until I made myself some Holy Pandas, so I had already lubed all the switches I needed. (Thankfully.) These popped in the hotswap sockets easily, making this part pretty easy. Though, I would like to add that these Zilent switches do not seem to be optimal for hotswap boards, as they do not securely hold on into the hotswap sockets. While they are firm enough for daily use, when you try to remove the keycap, the switch often pops right off of the socket along with the keycap. I don’t know if this is the switch’s fault, or the socket, or even the keycap, but just a warning. With that, and putting back the keycaps on the keyboard, I finished up the modding process for this board. This board was relatively a breeze to work on, as there were very little fiddely parts to work with with disassembly. I thought that the battery in the base might be a pain to work around, but as long I was careful with the cable attaching the battery to the PCB, it was fine. Just remember to purchase the right stabilizers to avoid the issue I had in this mod log. Review TLDR: ✔️65% Hotswap + Bluetooth killer combo, if you’re lazy and want a BT mech keeb with custom switches without soldering. ✔️Good compatibility with wide variety of systems. ✔️Suprisingly decent acoustics (with modding with sound dampening foam and lubing) ✔️Good price value. ❌Typing experience would be good if it wasn’t for cheap keycaps. ❌No easy customization or QMK. Some software promised in future, but unknown for now. ❌Somewhat weird layout. Overall best suited as a first 65% mech keyboard, secondary mobile keyboard, or a keyboard if you have a good keycap set to use. Prelude Before I talk about the keyboard, I want to talk briefly about the switches that came with the board. I ordered a board with Gateron Brown switches, mostly due to curiosity on how they felt to type on, and also because I love tactile switches and wanted to try them out. The short conclusion here is that Holy Pandas and ZealPC switches have ruined me, and these didn’t feel that tactile. Maybe a bit more tactile than Cherry Browns, but still not that great. Also, the switches felt too light for me, as I’m now used to 67g springs for my switches. Overall, not that great of an experience, but I was going to swap them out anyways, so I had no issue. I think if you just wanted a cheap entry into tactile switches without going all in, these would be fine though. Back to the elephant of the room that is the board itself, I feel like overall, the Keychron K6 is an excellent keyboard for the price (especially at the Kickstarter price) with a combination of features that aren’t seen a lot in other boards. But there are a few glaring issues that sadly do bring it down a bit that I’ll get to in a bit. The positives The biggest focus that I had when buying this specific board was the combination of two features that I just couldn’t find anywhere else: hotswappability and Bluetooth. Every other board out their has either hotswap sockets or Bluetooth. No other board in the 65% range that I could find had both of these features. Why was I looking for both Bluetooth and hotswapping though? Well, I was looking for a secondary keyboard to bring along wherever I go so I don’t need to type on mush wherever I go. For that, I found that Bluetooth is actually a killer feature, as going wireless on the go makes great sense, and allows me to use the keyboard with an iPad as well. But I also wanted to use the Zilents to get a tactile experience but silent enough to use in a public space. I could have gone for a soldering job with a 65% kit that supported Bluetooth, but I wanted more freedom of choice and ease of use, so I looked for a hotswap board as well. This led me on a search for a 65%, hotswap Bluetooth keyboard that was fruitless until the Keychron K6 came around. And so, how are the Bluetooth features? Well, I typed the entirety of the mod long part on my iPad with the Bluetooth feature on, and I’m happy to say it was a pretty decent experience. I had no issues typing everything up, and didn’t have much issues with latency as well. That was just for normal word processing work though. I wouldn’t really recommend just using this as a wireless gaming keyboard though. With Bluetooth 3.0, Keychron claims that you can connect up to three devices with up to 72 hours for the RGB version, and 68 for the white backlight version. While I haven’t used the K6 enough to benchmark those battery claims, the claimed 4000mAH battery seems pretty large enough to step up to that task. Multi-device pairing also worked great, with the keyboard switching between my iPad and my Galaxy S9 via keyboard shortcuts seamlessly after the initial Bluetooth sync process. For other features, the K6 also has different modes for Windows/Android and Mac/iOS, increasing the compatibility with the amount of devices you can use this with. The lighting is also good enough for normal backlight use. I purchased the white lighting, non-RGB version of the K6, and I’m finding the backlight adequate enough. As for acoustics, it was surprisingly decent. Through the sound dampening foam additions, as well as lubed stabilizers, I’m getting very little ping on the board. Not bad for a cheaper casing. With the combination of the Zilent v2 switches, I think this keyboard would be a great silent but tactile keyboard to use in public. Finally, there was the one thing I was worried about, it being the typing experience. I was worried about the height of the keyboard, as other Keychron keyboards were reported to be too high for comfortable types without a palm rest. But personally, I found it comfortable mostly, even for long-ish (30+ minutes) sessions of typing, without a palmrest or using a hovering technique. Though I do see why some people wouldn’t like using this keyboard for long sessions, I was mostly fine. However, there is another aspect of the typing experience that I wasn’t so happy about… The negatives Getting straight back to the typing experience, the included keycaps are pretty meh to bad. I’m not usually very picky about my keycaps, as I used stock keycaps for every keyboard I’ve owned. But these keycaps may make me think differently this time around. Honestly, the design is fine, with the subdued black keycaps with colored legends for the function keys and the orange highlight key for the lighting. These are extremely thin ABS keycaps however, that do feel somewhat cheap to type on. But the worst part about them, in my opinion, is the glossy and somewhat “sticky’ texture that they have. I don’t know if this will wear off as time goes on, but as of now, it really does lower the user experience a bit. Pretty mediocre, to even bad overall. Another issue is the lack of customizability and the nonstandard key layout. As of now, the K6 has no way first party way of customizing what your keyboard can do. No macros, switching key layouts, RGB/lighting customization features, nothing. You can use other software like Sharpkeys, as stated by Keychron, to remap some buttons, but that’s a pretty curveball way to solve the problem. Personally, I’m really missing a dedicated Delete key on my board, and would very much like to remap a key, like the light button, for Delete. The good news is that Keychron has promised customization software within the year for the K6, but that’s not a guarantee that I would bet on when making the purchase decision. And it’s no QMK, definitely. But hey, it’s got a lot of pretty lighting modes, right? right? Nonstandard layout is a smaller nitpick for me, but may not be for others, especially due to the quality of the keycaps. The K6 features two separate Function keys, which kind of makes finding a keycap set harder. Also, the bottom row is definitely nonstandard due to the Function keys as well. Though I am finding a lot of 65% boards to be nonstandard as well, so the K6 is not alone in this issue. But if you are shopping for a replacement keycap set for this board, it’s worth noting. Finally, there’re some more questionable design choices that personally are little naggling issues that aren’t too problematic, but worth mentioning. The USB-C port on the left side is one, making normal USB-C cables more of a pain to use. At least they include a braided, L-style USB-C cable that works better for this configuration. The large amount of empty space in the chassis is also a pointer of an odd design choice. Maybe it was for the battery, but that also doesn’t take too much space at all. It’s a weird choice that I needed to fix with foam to improve acoustics. Also, the aluminum version of the keyboard just being aluminum bar slide-on additions to the plastic model makes the aluminum model not worth to get, in my opinion. If you’re paying extra for aluminum, I’d expect a full aluminum machined case, not just 4 aluminum bars. The plastic chassis is also just a very meh design, as you can clearly see cut corners where the aluminum bars would have been slid in. Price / Conclusion Looking at both sides, I can attribute most of the cons of this device as probably cuts made to make the price as low as possible. The poor keycap quality, lack of customization or QMK, empty casing, and questionable aluminum version all seem to directly stem from price cuts. However, I don’t see that necessarily as a bad thing, and I see where the rest of the budget went into: hotswap and Bluetooth support, as well as wide device compatibility. On Keychron’s website, it’s currently $74 for a hotswap, white backlight version of the K6 (the one I got), excluding shipping, with the Kickstarter price trailing slightly behind at $69. I’d say if you’re looking for a 65% mechanical keyboard with a ton of core features for the cheap, the K6 is a pretty decent choice, especially if you already have a keycap set to use and don’t care too much about customization. I would find it harder to recommend if you are looking for more premium features like PBT caps and customization out of the box though. Don’t get the aluminum version though, it’s just not worth it. I’d also recommend this board if you’re someone like me and looking for a secondary that you want as a portable keyboard to use for your laptop or iPad when you’re out. That way, you can always have the best typing experience anywhere, with the added benefit of Bluetooth as well. I think I’m going to enjoy this board a lot outside of my desk. I’m just happy I got a Bluetooth 65% board for my Zilents. Now I just need to go waste even more money on PBT caps… But that’s a story for another time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Productivity System for 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2020/02/09/Productivity-System-for-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Productivity System for 2020" /><published>2020-02-09T01:31:23+09:00</published><updated>2020-02-09T01:31:23+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2020/02/09/Productivity-System-for-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2020/02/09/Productivity-System-for-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you need a wake-up call to realize something needs to change. For me, that was my next semester’s class schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All my schedules for the last year were pretty smooth sailing. None of them too jam-packed with tough classes, no 1st period 9AMs, good timings for lunch, etc. Not this semester’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-02-09productivity/everytime(2).png&quot; alt=&quot;Absolute garbage schedule.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While everything is in Korean, just looking at it at a glance, it already looks like terrible scheduling. 1st periods across the board from Monday to Friday (left to right), a 5 hours CompSci lab, and 3 classes in a row are all factors into making this semester look like a disaster. Not that I can do much about it anyways, since the mandatory classes lined up for me were poor by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After accepting this reality for the coming months, I took a look at how I did work for the past year and the tools I used to get that work done, and tried to see where I can make some changes to make my life less of a hell on earth and more of a manageable chaos. In that process of management, I decided to write this blogpost on the productivity system I’ll try to use for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analog-tool-bullet-journal&quot;&gt;Analog tool: Bullet Journal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of this year, I decided to look into Bullet Journaling, a proposed “new” method of both keeping track of your life and your tasks. In this process, I read “&lt;em&gt;The Bullet Journal Method&lt;/em&gt;” by Ryder Carroll, the creator of the Bullet Journal system, to make the decision if I should try using the system. While not all of the ideas and thoughts resonated with me completely, I decided that the system was valuable enough to give it a spin. So, I opened up my mostly dormant Traveler’s Notebook, and tried setting up the barebones of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t really give a solid conclusion on the system for myself yet. The fact that I’m on vacation and don’t really have many critical tasks yet kind of impacts how much I can get a use out of it yet. But I have found that keeping a short record of the daily tasks, events, and notes was satisfying. The journal allows me to take a look at past days and reflect on them, as well as set the next day up with intention. As to how well I follow those intentions is a work in progress, but I think it’ll be a great resource and tool for the upcoming semester. I think it’ll allow me to work with more intention in a busy and tiring semester, as well as reflect on how every day went by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, this also gives me an excuse to put my fountain pen to good use, so I might as well kill two birds with one stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analog-tool-coffee&quot;&gt;Analog tool: Coffee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right. This isn’t a new one by any shot, but the way I’m going to be keeping down this black magic liquid is going to change with this semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 9AMs every day, and a commune time of around 1 and a half hours, I’m going to need the caffeine to get through the day, moreso than the past. To lower the amount of money I waste on getting that caffeine, as well as to actually get a good experience out of it, I decided to invest in a coffee grinder and brew my own coffee every day. Might as well make most of the situation that I’ve been thrown into, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conveniently, there’s a local roaster literally a walk down the road from my university that roasts the beans on the spot with the order, so I think I could get a really good experience from this venture. Honestly, can’t wait to try this new coffee out, as all I’ve been drinking is pregrinded coffee or coffee brewed from a store. It’s going to be pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-do-list-todoist&quot;&gt;To-do list: Todoist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally getting into the more digital side of things, I decided to change up my todo list application from TickTick to Todoist. While there’s nothing wrong with TickTick, I found that in the past, there was a lot of friction between me inputting tasks into TickTick. So I decided to try moving to Todoist for a while and trial it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the natural language processing for Todoist is already showing to be a lot better that TickTick, albeit there was some issues with notifications for a task that I set for a day. I still need to get used to this new tool, but I am looking forwards to make more use of Todoist with work in the future. The more positive reception among people who use it and the features focused on productivity do make me want to keep on trying it though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calendar-google-calendar&quot;&gt;Calendar: Google Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have actually never made use of a calendar application before. Kind of surprising, but I just never found a good use for in my working life. I figured that I didn’t really need one, and if I did need to remember an event, I could just use a to-do list app (though I actually never used even a to-do list app very well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-02-09productivity/googlecal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Absolute garbage schedule, but on Google Calendar.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to start putting a calendar to use in my system, I jumped into Google Calendar and started inputting that horrendous schedule as a calendar. As school hasn’t started for me yet, I don’t have much to add here yet, but I could see various calendars being created here to separate school clubs and events, as well as personal calendars for my own personal work and deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-the-to-do-list-and-calendar-tag-team&quot;&gt;Managing the To-do list and Calendar tag team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, there is a lot of intertwining areas between a to-do list and a calendar app, and to use them both effectively, I decided to put some ways to use both these applications effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The to-do list app would hold all the tasks that I need to get done, but I can get it done anytime before the due date. This would include such as homework assignments, exam review, and personal project work. The calendar app on the other hand will contain events that I have to be present for. These include supplementary classes, club meetings, and exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may have seemed obvious, but I was struggling to understand why one would need to use both systems, when it seemed like the two types of applications were interchangeable. For some people, it might as well be. But I want to try using both systems for different types of tasks so that I can get the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also thinking of implementing the analog Bullet Journal system here as a sort of a “hopper”. In the bullet journal, I’ll take a look at my calendar and to-do list and see the tasks that I need and want to get done, and input them in the journal. This way, I’d be able to make sure no tasks get left behind, and to also assure I can do my tasks with more intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, by using both systems as a tag team, with the Bullet Journal also being thrown in, I feel like I could get around without forgetting something important or missing some homework or project work that I needed to have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;note-system-notion&quot;&gt;Note(?) system: Notion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the more new tool in the system, but in the last few months, I started using Notion as mostly a note taking system, but also to keep track of a lot of things in my life. In fact, I migrated all the blog writing to Notion, and I’m writing this blog entry in Notion right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion is kind of a complicated tool to describe. It seems to be primarily a note taking application, but it can do so much more. One of the standout features are the databases, which allow you to organize and keep track of your information better than a normal note would do. For example, I currently use a database keeping track of all the subscription services that I use, and how much I have to pay per month. Another way that I am looking to use these databases are to organize art commissions that I may start taking in the future (as long as I can actually get good at drawing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization system is also very interesting, as you basically create what is essentially a webpage from the tools Notion gives you, and fill it with information or links to other pages. This allows you create a sort of a homepage where everything in connected and easily accessible, which is a feature that I really like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-02-09productivity/Notion.png&quot; alt=&quot;My current Notion homepage.&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion definitely isn’t perfect, and there are a lot of areas where it can use work. The mobile apps are pretty bad, with slow loading times. While there are a lot of connections with other third-party services, I would like more. Some features that I also want are the ability to create forms in Notion to use for clients, and to aggregate responses in the databases. There’s no stylus support, so the only way to input data is on the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I do point out these missing features and issues, Notion still is quite the powerful tool, and I aim to continue learning how to make the most out of it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;handwriting-system-notability&quot;&gt;Handwriting System: Notability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did state in the Notion section that one of its main weaknesses is no handwriting support. While I do like to write a lot by typing, for studying and taking notes, especially for subjects like math, handwriting is definitely the way to go. For this, instead of using paper, I’ve grown to use the iPad and the Apple Pencil for digital handwriting, with my app of choice being Notability. I’ve used Notability for a while, and all the features are a must for a student. You have access to a variety of types of paper for whatever subject matter, ass well as a variety of writing tools you’ll need, such as a highlighter. The killer feature is the audio recording though, as it records audio as you take notes, which allows you to go back easily to the audio section of a certain point of your notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, while I do find that I don’t go back and look at my class notes very often, I find it useful to keep myself focused during class, and taking notes during class does allow me to digest the course material better. Also, I find it very useful to use Notability to make things like review sheets, as well as a endless whiteboard of solving practice problems. It’s really been a gamechanger in how I do study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notability, and as an extension the iPad itself, as a whole just made studying and especially using eBook textbooks a lot easier. From lugging around heavy textbooks to holding a tablet device, it really did make life easier as a learning student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must stop here, because going further from here would make this post get off-topic from a productivity system post to a studying app post. Though that isn’t that bad of an idea. I may or may not do a “What’s on my phone/tablet” post just for the sake of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I really want to focus on building a productivity system this semester that I’ll actually use, and more importantly, keep me working and productive. I think writing this post allowed me to gather my thoughts on building that system, and thus get me to actually see reason to use the system. Think I’ll also write a post later on in the semester on how this system is going, and the adjustments that I want to make to it, if any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Sometimes you need a wake-up call to realize something needs to change. For me, that was my next semester’s class schedule.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">End of year review - 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/12/24/End-of-year-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End of year review - 2019" /><published>2019-12-24T00:20:22+09:00</published><updated>2019-12-24T00:20:22+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/12/24/End%20of%20year%20review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/12/24/End-of-year-review.html">&lt;p&gt;2019, another year gone. What a year it was, with ups and downs. This year was filled with discoveries and new experiences, especially with starting university back in my home country, but also with a lot of roadblocks and nasty encounters with issues such as academics and social encounters. But that’s all to be expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I wanted to go over some of the key points that I went through this year, positive and negative, and also some things that I want to work on as personal projects for this winter vacation (and beyond into the next year/decade).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;university---the-ups-and-downs&quot;&gt;University - the ups and downs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 was the year that I finally exited the hellhole that is university admissions and actually started university. Initial reactions to the acceptance was basically elation. I actually didn’t expect myself to get into the university that I got into, and expected myself to go into a “lower tier” university. But amongst the waitlist results, I was able to barely make my way in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting into university, studying was a mixed bag. Some subjects were fine, thanks to prior experience and learning in the IB, while other classes were pretty tough. Some classes that were tough especially were the calculus and physics lab classes. Calculus was mainly due to the fact that I’m simply terrible at calculus. I especially had issues within an exam situation where my weaknesses in memorization of techniques. Physics lab was painful mostly due to the extreme amount of work required. A long lab report, handwritten, every week for a semester was simply just brutal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But overall, the classes that I did find interest in, such as the CS courses that I had to take (discrete mathematics), were worth listening and learning about. I think I was able to get valuable information that I wasn’t able to get before in high school, and I do feel good about each new concept that I am able to pick up. Even if the concept is tough or if I had to self-study a lot of the material, I found it rewarding to learn these new concepts. Generally, I found university to be overall a positive experience, but with some tough spots here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;clubs-and-social-life---a-tough-one&quot;&gt;Clubs and social life - a tough one&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social life is always a tough one for me. I was never the most sociable guy, and in the past, I usually had a tight-knit small group of friends, and nothing really more. So when I threw myself into a new country, in a new school with new people, with a language that I wasn’t necessarily the most familiar with (albeit my native language, somewhat surprisingly), it was really hard to get used with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly looked towards school clubs at my school to interact with more like-minded people. Currently, I’m associated with two clubs, a computer science club orientated towards projects, and an anime/manga club that is primarily focused on drawing and discussion. It’s mostly worked pretty well, as I did indeed meet a lot of people that I enjoyed being with, quickly filling up the hole of loneliness from leaving my old friends from abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes, I still feel like that there’s some issues that I’m just not able to mend up. Small things like the difference in jargon and memes in Korean that I don’t know ended up causing problems. I felt that if I had I lived in Korea more and put more effort into exposing myself to these new things, I would have had an easier time getting used to everything. So I guess a lot of it was mostly my fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even so, I feel like there’s some unexplainable little thing that I’m missing here in social life here. Talking to others is still somewhat awkward, stumbling with words and wondering if I should actually say something. Sometimes, I feel like I’m the third wheel in a group, as if I’m merely tagging along, and not considered as a core member of a group. I don’t know what I could do to make it better, but I’d like to work on this area more next year around in social life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never easy socially, but I am really thankful for those around me that have kept me company over the past year when I was struggling in a new environment. Guess all I can do is try my best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-hobbies---drawing&quot;&gt;New hobbies - Drawing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, as part of joining the anime/manga in my club, I also started to self-learn how to draw. I’ve never serious picked up a pen to draw before, but this year in September, I finally started attempting the uphill road in art. It started pretty rough, as I didn’t know the basics at all. While that first starting point was somewhat depressing, I’m quite happy that I did stick with the process. I purchased a book to get me started on learning the basics of drawing, and I even got into it enough that I invested in a drawing tablet for my computer. Both were pretty invaluable to the whole illustration business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, 3 months into this new hobby, I feel like I did get a lot better than where I started from. I can finally draw something that looks like a person, and while I’m not completely happy with it, I do figure that it is good enough when I look at how much work I’ve put into it in a short period of time. I’m continuously trying to challenge myself with new poses and unfamiliar scenes, and I do hope I’m getting better with all the practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m really happy about picking up drawing. I’d thought I’d never produce anything from it, but I think I can actually get some work with the medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;goals-for-the-new-year&quot;&gt;Goals for the new year&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the new coming year, I do want to try some new things to change my life around just a little bit more for my own benefit (maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be more organized and productive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try starting commissions for art.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Actually maintain good habits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one is a pretty abstract goal, but something that I do want to put some work into for this next year. This year overall was productive enough to get everything done, but I think I could do better, and for this next year, I want to try to organize my life a bit more so that I can get a lot more done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I tried to implement more productivity tools, such as a todo list, into my workflow this year, but I usually found myself not using it when I should have, and often forgot to input important tasks into the todo list. This year, I want to find new methods to remedy these kinds of issues in organization and productivity. This is partly why I’m trying implementing Notion into my workflow, to see if I can get a lot of the stuff I work on into one working space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second one mainly came from after learning how to draw. I certainly don’t feel like my work isn’t good enough to sell to anyone just yet. However, I do want to get good enough to a point where someone can look at some sample art that I’ve created and want some art created by me for themselves. In the next year, I want to make it an objective to get good enough to maybe open up for commissions and see how far I could get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the third goal is going to be a hard one. Throughout the year, I’ve started some more healthier activities into my daily life, such as exercise. I was also getting a lot more benefit from the exercise, such as being more positive overall. However, due to factors such as academic duties and the overwhelming pressure of finals, I had to put it on hold for a while. This time, however, I want to integrate such positive habits like exercise on a schedule in which even if I’m busy, I’d always have time to perform the habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heading-into-2020&quot;&gt;Heading into 2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all that has happened last year, and even in the last decade, I do hope that 2020, hey, let’s also say the next decade, can be one for the better. Just saying that won’t bring it however, I definitely need to put in the work. I’d like to think that I’m ready for that work that I need to put in, but I’m not sure if I’m certain about that. I’d still like to think that I want to put in the work, so I’m hoping that I am really ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a better year, and a better decade.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">2019, another year gone. What a year it was, with ups and downs. This year was filled with discoveries and new experiences, especially with starting university back in my home country, but also with a lot of roadblocks and nasty encounters with issues such as academics and social encounters. But that’s all to be expected.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keyboard buildlog - The quest for the Holy Pandas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2019/12/10/keyboard-buildog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keyboard buildlog - The quest for the Holy Pandas" /><published>2019-12-10T00:13:30+09:00</published><updated>2019-12-10T00:13:30+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2019/12/10/keyboard%20buildog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2019/12/10/keyboard-buildog.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest interests I’ve got currently are custom mechanical keyboards. On the surface, mechanical keyboards can be pretty dry. After all, for many starters, there’s mostly the gaming brands of keyboards, along with one brand of choice for switches, that being Cherry. But stepping outside that bubble, there’s another giant world of custom keyboard options, from keyboard layouts and PCBs, keycaps, lubes, and espically keyswitches. Gateron, Kailh, Zealios, are all names in the enthusiast mechanical keyboard community that make switches outside of Cherry. But there’s one switch that’s basically been heralded as legendary in the community - the Holy Panda. For this keyboard build, I finally get to experience the Holy Panda- well, actually a clone of it. Actually, a clone of a clone of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction---the-holy-panda&quot;&gt;Introduction - The Holy Panda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Panda is very tactile keyboard switch that requires a lot of assembly. It’s essentially a “frankenswitch”, a switch that mixes parts from two different switches, the Invyr Panda and the Halo Clear/True switches. The Halo Clear/True switches are produced and sold by Drop (formally known as Massdrop, which name I prefer), and are relatively easy to acquire now. But the Invyr Pandas, well, they are very much an endangererd species of switches. First produced as a group buy as a normal linear switch, nobody really gave it a second thought, as it wasn’t a very good switch as well in the first place. But, when a certain community member started mixing around parts of switches, and put in the stem of a Halo Clear/True switch inside the housing of a Invyr Panda switch, and one of the world’s most tactile switches were born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most defining traits of the Holy Pandas was their distinct tactility. While others can produce a tactile switch that is very tactile, many saw the Holy Pandas as just better than others. For one, it had pre-travel, meaning that the switch had a certain point of movement between the start of the press and the point where the tactile bump starts, leading for some to have a better feeling. Also, the tactility was described to be as very “round”, meaning that the tactility stayed longer for the duration of the press, and is more gradual than other tactile switches. These contributions just made the Holy Pandas a unique tactile switch that others simpily couldn’t replicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another distinct trait was the sound of the switches. Many regarded the sound of the Holy Pandas as one of the best sounding, espically when properly lubed and inside a case with great acoustics, such as cases made with brass. In fact, there are a ton of YouTube videos showing the typing sound of a Holy Panda, and the comments ooze with praise of the sound. Both the traits of the tactility and the sound made them a highly sought switch for people that were searching for the pinnicale of tactility of a keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-drama-with-the-holy-panda&quot;&gt;The drama with the Holy Panda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would think that a keyboard switch is one of the most mundane topics that cannot possibly generate any controversy, but strap on, because the story of the Holy Pandas is a bumpy one. When I said the Invyr Pandas were endangered, it was a true statement. There were very little group purchases for the switches, and at the time, I could only assume that people were not as enthusiastic to buy the Pandas, as the switches by itself weren’t great. But by the time the combination with the Halo Clear/True stems were found and the Holy Pandas were born, the Invyr Panda group buys were long gone. To make matters worse, it was revealed that the moulds for the original Panda housings were destroyed and lost, leading to the price of the Invyr Pandas and also the Holy Pandas to skyrocket. At one point, these Holy Pandas were going for 5 dollars per switch. That’s some outrageous pricing, as even the most expensive switches today go for 12 dollars for 10 switches (thank zeal tax).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bubble of the pricing had to pop, and it did. New movements started to form to reprouduce the Holy Pandas, with two sides headlining it. One side was Massdrop (now Drop), collaborating with the original Invyr, the original Panda switch maker to repair the switch moulds and reproduce Holy Pandas under the original name. Another side was a company going by BSUN, who also produce keyswitches amonst a lot of other electronics parts. They made the BSUN GSUS, a clone of the Invyr Pandas, and started a limited group buy for the switches. Naturally, the community was skeptical of both sides, but at the end, it was confirmed that both the Massdrop Holy Pandas and the BSUN GSUS switches were legitimate, or good enough to be indifferentiable from the originals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we come to YOK. This group(?) produced a switch that was said to be a clone of the BSUN GSUS, which itself is a clone of the Invyr Pandas. This was how far Holy Pandas got. People were willing to pay for a switch that is a clone of a clone of a switch. Anyways, more skeptism started to brew, but this switch was also seen as a legitmate alternative to make Holy Pandas. YOK started with maroon red housings, which were dubed as Holy Red Pandas after assembly, and now has mint green, black, and blue variants, all with different names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s enough of a history lesson for the Holy Panda switch. A long and needlessly complicated history. Coming back to the present, I got myself the original YOK Red Pandas, the Halo Clear switches that came with my Massdrop ALT keyboard, and some other parts to make these legendary switches, and try them myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-chosen-parts&quot;&gt;The Chosen Parts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Switch 1: YOK Red Pandas
One of the main subjects that I talked about in the past section, the YOK Pandas are one of the only reliably available sources of Invyr Panda clones. With the Invyr Pandas long dead, the GSUS being a one-off group buy, the YOK Pandas are still sold on a variety of stores. I decided to choose the Red Pandas, mostly for the unique color. After all, what other switch is maroon red like this one. Since I’ve already talked back and front about these, I’ll skip talking more about these.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Switch 2: Massdrop Halo Clears
The perfect sacrifice for stem parts, I ordered these with the Massdrop ALT keyboard. It wasn’t for the Holy Pandas, as back then there were no notice of the GSUS being produced at that point, and buying Pandas was clearly a lost cause. I did want to try them out, so I made the choice. While these switches were pretty tactile enough, the spring were just way too heavy, and the typing experience was significantly hampered because of these. So, to put them into better use than stick them in the closet and collect dust, better to put them into use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lube: Tribosys 3203
Yes, people lube keyboard switches. While losing some of the tactility, to raise the smoothness of the switches, many people decide to take the time to lube the switches. For a while, Krytox was king in the selection, but recently, a hybrid type of lube called Tribosys came out, and has been very popular for many keyboard enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds, 3203 and 3204, with the 4 being more thicker and preferable for linear switches, with 3 being better for tactile. I went for the 3203, but many other people, such as TaehaTypes, have also been using 3204 as well. I think that it doesn’t really too matter for the Holy Panda or its clones, as the switch is so tactile by itself, so 3204 may even be better for some if the switch proves to be too tactile for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Springs: 1UpKeyboards 67g gold plated springs
One of the biggest issues of the YOK Pandas was that the springs included with them have horrible spring crunch/ping. Spring crunch is a type of sound that comes from lower quality switches where an audible crunch can be heard whenever the spring is compressed. I didn’t want that for my switches, and I also didn’t like the weight of the springs, so I decided to pick up some new springs as well. So with this, I also was able to do some spring swapping as well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Switchopener: The Switchcracker 2:
I already used this tool to open up some keyboard switches for a previous project, and now it’s being used again. It is one of the cheapest options that you can find out there to open switches, outside of a flat-head screwdriver, and it is obvious why, as it is a 3D printed plastic switch opener. While it does get the job done, there were some issues with it that may be only on my model, it still got the job done. I’ll get back to this tool later.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process-the-highs-and-the-lows&quot;&gt;The process: the highs and the lows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall process for this keyboard modification looked like this:
	1. Extract all the stems from the Halo Clears.
	2. Open up the YOK Pandas and remove the springs and the stem.
	3. Lube the housing, new springs, and stem carefully and put together the switch.
	4. Install the finished Holy Red Panda in the keyboard.
	5. Repeat.
A simple process, right? On paper, yes. But actually going through the entire process, some parts were a nightmare, especially part 1 and 4. Let’s get through each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-the-stems-holding-the-urge-to-throw-the-switchcracker-out-the-window&quot;&gt;Getting the stems: holding the urge to throw the Switchcracker out the window&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening the switch of the Halo Clears was not easy at all. In the choices of switches one has in the market today, there are two kinds of switches based on the locking mechanism of the switch. The Cherry style switch, with 4 clips, two on each side, and the Kailh switch, with two big clips. The Switchcracker had prongs that can open both the Cherry and Kailh style switches, and it can open the Cherries really well, but the Kailh…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s pretty bad. The fact that it took like an hour to open around 8 switches shows how frustrating my experience was with my product. The Kailh clips didn’t match with the placement of the prongs on the Switchcracker, which lead to the switch to just not open on the first try. In fact, it took many tries for a single switch. The worst part was I needed to absolutely get through every switch, as I had exactly 67 switches for 67 keys, and I couldn’t just skip one and move on. I needed all the stems without fail. This did take around two infuriating days, and I was able to get the job done at the end, but it did take much too effort than it should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really did want to throw that plastic tool at a wall, but I was able to get the job done. In the future, I would have gone with a metal switchopener that would have higher precision in manufacturing and probably allow for a more easier process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opening-and-lubing-the-yoks--the-better-part-of-the-process&quot;&gt;Opening and Lubing the YOKs — the better part of the process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a much easier process than the previous part. The Switchcracker’s Cherry MX opening prongs are far better designed, and the YOK Pandas use the Cherry MX locking mechanism, so opening the switches was a breeze. Also, since this isn’t the first time that I’ve lubed keyboard switches, the process of lubing did go a lot faster, and I overall used a lot less lube than I did before, so I could see that as a win for this keyboard build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while this process was still the most tedious part of the build, as lubing switches isn’t the most entertaining thing to do, it was still relatively painless compared to the other parts of this keyboard build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to another painful part of this build however…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;installing-the-holy-red-pandas---wanting-to-hammer-in-the-switches-on-the-board&quot;&gt;Installing the Holy Red Pandas - Wanting to hammer in the switches on the board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing these Holy Red Pandas was not an easy task. I think that these switches aren’t built for hotswap-boards, and were intended to be used for boards that used solder. So when I tried to install these switches in my keyboard, there were a lot of fitting issues for some of the switches. For example, some switches simply refused to be inserted firmly in the sockets, which required a lot of force to basically force it in. This basically lead to a lot of sore fingers by the end, which was not pleasant at all to deal with. If these switches weren’t either expensive or somewhat fragile, I would have liked to take a hammer to the switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in this process I realized that some of the switches were just defects. Thankfully, I ordered 70 switches, meaning I had three left over to use. This made the defects easily replaceable, but if I didn’t have extra, I would have been left with an incomplete keyboard build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the end, I was able to get every switch in the keyboard and get everything working. By the end of the build, it took more than a day due to all the issues from opening the switches and installing the switches. But it was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-conclusion-and-review&quot;&gt;Final conclusion and review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… After all of that painstaking work, the question remains. Was it worth getting these switches. For me, the answer was “Yes, somewhat.”. These switches are the most tactile switches that I have used, and as a fan of tactile keyboards, typing on it is a great pleasure. Every task that requires a long typing session, like writing this blog, is a pleasure to write because of the tactile experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for the amount of work required for this build, and the price involved in purchasing these switches, I wouldn’t recommend it to everyone. I was somewhat lucky having Halo Clears on me already, but if you are starting fresh, you would need both the Halo Clears and one of the Panda variants, leading to around $140 for a 70 switch keyboard total. That’s not a small amount of money. Also with the time required to put those keyboards in a custom keyboard is also long, and other parts for a custom keyboard is also expensive. So unless you’re an absolute keyboard nut like me, I wouldn’t really recommend it, and would point you towards other more mainstream options that stil feel decently tactile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as a personal device, I’m glad that I was able to get the Holy Panda experience, and I’m basically keeping these switches to use for my daily typing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, hopefully you enjoyed coming along the journey of the writeup of a somewhat mundane keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="tech" /><summary type="html">One of the biggest interests I’ve got currently are custom mechanical keyboards. On the surface, mechanical keyboards can be pretty dry. After all, for many starters, there’s mostly the gaming brands of keyboards, along with one brand of choice for switches, that being Cherry. But stepping outside that bubble, there’s another giant world of custom keyboard options, from keyboard layouts and PCBs, keycaps, lubes, and espically keyswitches. Gateron, Kailh, Zealios, are all names in the enthusiast mechanical keyboard community that make switches outside of Cherry. But there’s one switch that’s basically been heralded as legendary in the community - the Holy Panda. For this keyboard build, I finally get to experience the Holy Panda- well, actually a clone of it. Actually, a clone of a clone of it. Introduction - The Holy Panda The Holy Panda is very tactile keyboard switch that requires a lot of assembly. It’s essentially a “frankenswitch”, a switch that mixes parts from two different switches, the Invyr Panda and the Halo Clear/True switches. The Halo Clear/True switches are produced and sold by Drop (formally known as Massdrop, which name I prefer), and are relatively easy to acquire now. But the Invyr Pandas, well, they are very much an endangererd species of switches. First produced as a group buy as a normal linear switch, nobody really gave it a second thought, as it wasn’t a very good switch as well in the first place. But, when a certain community member started mixing around parts of switches, and put in the stem of a Halo Clear/True switch inside the housing of a Invyr Panda switch, and one of the world’s most tactile switches were born. One of the most defining traits of the Holy Pandas was their distinct tactility. While others can produce a tactile switch that is very tactile, many saw the Holy Pandas as just better than others. For one, it had pre-travel, meaning that the switch had a certain point of movement between the start of the press and the point where the tactile bump starts, leading for some to have a better feeling. Also, the tactility was described to be as very “round”, meaning that the tactility stayed longer for the duration of the press, and is more gradual than other tactile switches. These contributions just made the Holy Pandas a unique tactile switch that others simpily couldn’t replicate. Another distinct trait was the sound of the switches. Many regarded the sound of the Holy Pandas as one of the best sounding, espically when properly lubed and inside a case with great acoustics, such as cases made with brass. In fact, there are a ton of YouTube videos showing the typing sound of a Holy Panda, and the comments ooze with praise of the sound. Both the traits of the tactility and the sound made them a highly sought switch for people that were searching for the pinnicale of tactility of a keyboard. The drama with the Holy Panda You would think that a keyboard switch is one of the most mundane topics that cannot possibly generate any controversy, but strap on, because the story of the Holy Pandas is a bumpy one. When I said the Invyr Pandas were endangered, it was a true statement. There were very little group purchases for the switches, and at the time, I could only assume that people were not as enthusiastic to buy the Pandas, as the switches by itself weren’t great. But by the time the combination with the Halo Clear/True stems were found and the Holy Pandas were born, the Invyr Panda group buys were long gone. To make matters worse, it was revealed that the moulds for the original Panda housings were destroyed and lost, leading to the price of the Invyr Pandas and also the Holy Pandas to skyrocket. At one point, these Holy Pandas were going for 5 dollars per switch. That’s some outrageous pricing, as even the most expensive switches today go for 12 dollars for 10 switches (thank zeal tax). The bubble of the pricing had to pop, and it did. New movements started to form to reprouduce the Holy Pandas, with two sides headlining it. One side was Massdrop (now Drop), collaborating with the original Invyr, the original Panda switch maker to repair the switch moulds and reproduce Holy Pandas under the original name. Another side was a company going by BSUN, who also produce keyswitches amonst a lot of other electronics parts. They made the BSUN GSUS, a clone of the Invyr Pandas, and started a limited group buy for the switches. Naturally, the community was skeptical of both sides, but at the end, it was confirmed that both the Massdrop Holy Pandas and the BSUN GSUS switches were legitimate, or good enough to be indifferentiable from the originals. Finally, we come to YOK. This group(?) produced a switch that was said to be a clone of the BSUN GSUS, which itself is a clone of the Invyr Pandas. This was how far Holy Pandas got. People were willing to pay for a switch that is a clone of a clone of a switch. Anyways, more skeptism started to brew, but this switch was also seen as a legitmate alternative to make Holy Pandas. YOK started with maroon red housings, which were dubed as Holy Red Pandas after assembly, and now has mint green, black, and blue variants, all with different names. Well that’s enough of a history lesson for the Holy Panda switch. A long and needlessly complicated history. Coming back to the present, I got myself the original YOK Red Pandas, the Halo Clear switches that came with my Massdrop ALT keyboard, and some other parts to make these legendary switches, and try them myself. The Chosen Parts: Switch 1: YOK Red Pandas One of the main subjects that I talked about in the past section, the YOK Pandas are one of the only reliably available sources of Invyr Panda clones. With the Invyr Pandas long dead, the GSUS being a one-off group buy, the YOK Pandas are still sold on a variety of stores. I decided to choose the Red Pandas, mostly for the unique color. After all, what other switch is maroon red like this one. Since I’ve already talked back and front about these, I’ll skip talking more about these. Switch 2: Massdrop Halo Clears The perfect sacrifice for stem parts, I ordered these with the Massdrop ALT keyboard. It wasn’t for the Holy Pandas, as back then there were no notice of the GSUS being produced at that point, and buying Pandas was clearly a lost cause. I did want to try them out, so I made the choice. While these switches were pretty tactile enough, the spring were just way too heavy, and the typing experience was significantly hampered because of these. So, to put them into better use than stick them in the closet and collect dust, better to put them into use. Lube: Tribosys 3203 Yes, people lube keyboard switches. While losing some of the tactility, to raise the smoothness of the switches, many people decide to take the time to lube the switches. For a while, Krytox was king in the selection, but recently, a hybrid type of lube called Tribosys came out, and has been very popular for many keyboard enthusiasts. There are two kinds, 3203 and 3204, with the 4 being more thicker and preferable for linear switches, with 3 being better for tactile. I went for the 3203, but many other people, such as TaehaTypes, have also been using 3204 as well. I think that it doesn’t really too matter for the Holy Panda or its clones, as the switch is so tactile by itself, so 3204 may even be better for some if the switch proves to be too tactile for some. Springs: 1UpKeyboards 67g gold plated springs One of the biggest issues of the YOK Pandas was that the springs included with them have horrible spring crunch/ping. Spring crunch is a type of sound that comes from lower quality switches where an audible crunch can be heard whenever the spring is compressed. I didn’t want that for my switches, and I also didn’t like the weight of the springs, so I decided to pick up some new springs as well. So with this, I also was able to do some spring swapping as well. Switchopener: The Switchcracker 2: I already used this tool to open up some keyboard switches for a previous project, and now it’s being used again. It is one of the cheapest options that you can find out there to open switches, outside of a flat-head screwdriver, and it is obvious why, as it is a 3D printed plastic switch opener. While it does get the job done, there were some issues with it that may be only on my model, it still got the job done. I’ll get back to this tool later. The process: the highs and the lows The overall process for this keyboard modification looked like this: 1. Extract all the stems from the Halo Clears. 2. Open up the YOK Pandas and remove the springs and the stem. 3. Lube the housing, new springs, and stem carefully and put together the switch. 4. Install the finished Holy Red Panda in the keyboard. 5. Repeat. A simple process, right? On paper, yes. But actually going through the entire process, some parts were a nightmare, especially part 1 and 4. Let’s get through each step. Getting the stems: holding the urge to throw the Switchcracker out the window Opening the switch of the Halo Clears was not easy at all. In the choices of switches one has in the market today, there are two kinds of switches based on the locking mechanism of the switch. The Cherry style switch, with 4 clips, two on each side, and the Kailh switch, with two big clips. The Switchcracker had prongs that can open both the Cherry and Kailh style switches, and it can open the Cherries really well, but the Kailh… Well, it’s pretty bad. The fact that it took like an hour to open around 8 switches shows how frustrating my experience was with my product. The Kailh clips didn’t match with the placement of the prongs on the Switchcracker, which lead to the switch to just not open on the first try. In fact, it took many tries for a single switch. The worst part was I needed to absolutely get through every switch, as I had exactly 67 switches for 67 keys, and I couldn’t just skip one and move on. I needed all the stems without fail. This did take around two infuriating days, and I was able to get the job done at the end, but it did take much too effort than it should have. I really did want to throw that plastic tool at a wall, but I was able to get the job done. In the future, I would have gone with a metal switchopener that would have higher precision in manufacturing and probably allow for a more easier process. Opening and Lubing the YOKs — the better part of the process This was a much easier process than the previous part. The Switchcracker’s Cherry MX opening prongs are far better designed, and the YOK Pandas use the Cherry MX locking mechanism, so opening the switches was a breeze. Also, since this isn’t the first time that I’ve lubed keyboard switches, the process of lubing did go a lot faster, and I overall used a lot less lube than I did before, so I could see that as a win for this keyboard build. So while this process was still the most tedious part of the build, as lubing switches isn’t the most entertaining thing to do, it was still relatively painless compared to the other parts of this keyboard build. Going back to another painful part of this build however… Installing the Holy Red Pandas - Wanting to hammer in the switches on the board Installing these Holy Red Pandas was not an easy task. I think that these switches aren’t built for hotswap-boards, and were intended to be used for boards that used solder. So when I tried to install these switches in my keyboard, there were a lot of fitting issues for some of the switches. For example, some switches simply refused to be inserted firmly in the sockets, which required a lot of force to basically force it in. This basically lead to a lot of sore fingers by the end, which was not pleasant at all to deal with. If these switches weren’t either expensive or somewhat fragile, I would have liked to take a hammer to the switch. Also, in this process I realized that some of the switches were just defects. Thankfully, I ordered 70 switches, meaning I had three left over to use. This made the defects easily replaceable, but if I didn’t have extra, I would have been left with an incomplete keyboard build. But at the end, I was able to get every switch in the keyboard and get everything working. By the end of the build, it took more than a day due to all the issues from opening the switches and installing the switches. But it was done. Final conclusion and review So… After all of that painstaking work, the question remains. Was it worth getting these switches. For me, the answer was “Yes, somewhat.”. These switches are the most tactile switches that I have used, and as a fan of tactile keyboards, typing on it is a great pleasure. Every task that requires a long typing session, like writing this blog, is a pleasure to write because of the tactile experience. However, for the amount of work required for this build, and the price involved in purchasing these switches, I wouldn’t recommend it to everyone. I was somewhat lucky having Halo Clears on me already, but if you are starting fresh, you would need both the Halo Clears and one of the Panda variants, leading to around $140 for a 70 switch keyboard total. That’s not a small amount of money. Also with the time required to put those keyboards in a custom keyboard is also long, and other parts for a custom keyboard is also expensive. So unless you’re an absolute keyboard nut like me, I wouldn’t really recommend it, and would point you towards other more mainstream options that stil feel decently tactile. But as a personal device, I’m glad that I was able to get the Holy Panda experience, and I’m basically keeping these switches to use for my daily typing experience. Anyways, hopefully you enjoyed coming along the journey of the writeup of a somewhat mundane keyboard.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What makes a good game?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/games/2019/10/27/What-makes-a-good-game.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What makes a good game?" /><published>2019-10-27T16:45:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-27T16:45:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/games/2019/10/27/What%20makes%20a%20good%20game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/games/2019/10/27/What-makes-a-good-game.html">&lt;p&gt;Since writing up the past CrossCode and Factorio game review, I’ve been thinking about what makes a good game in the first place. What sorts from the good from the bad, and maybe from the good and the best? While thinking about this, I’ve thought of some “tier list”, or rather what matters the most when it comes to a good game, and what doesn’t matter as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, this is a very personal list that is completely based on my opinions. Everyone’s priorities are always different, but this is just my choice of qualities. A tier list of factors based on importance probably isn’t even the best idea, but I wanted to write about it anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-most-integral-centermost-part-of-a-game-gameplay&quot;&gt;The most integral, centermost part of a game: Gameplay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably very obvious, but it goes over our heads a lot. A game needs to have great gameplay to even go as a passable game. If the gameplay aspect just doesn’t work well with the player, then it simply can’t be a great of a game. This has started to become forgotten a lot due to focuses in other areas of games, such as graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the definition of gameplay is way too vast and out of the scope of the blogpost like this. A visual novel would have a completely different gameplay style compared to than an action RPG. But what I am willing to say is that the game’s gameplay must be appropriate to the genre of the game, as well as fun to play with and frustrating to play against. Various elements of gameplay could be movement mechanics, combat system, map/level design, character level progression, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to go through various examples of games with good (and bad) game mechanics. Taking a look at CrossCode and Factorio, two games I’ve recently played and put my thoughts up on this blog, both have great elements of gameplay. With CrossCode, the combat mechanics and level design are both great gameplay elements that I’ve enjoyed greatly, and Factorio’s utter commitment to gameplay through automation is almost overwhelming. However, CrossCode’s crafting and farming mechanics isn’t the most enjoyable gameplay you can have in a game, and sometimes, the dungeons dragged on far too long for my taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seen from these examples, games need a good balance of gameplay elements. Too much gameplay elements to take in, and the player may feel overwhelmed with everything. Too shallow, and the game becomes boring. CrossCode and Factorio both have a good balance most of the time, but sometimes as seen before, it’s not perfect. But hey, nothing is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-1-b-to-the-1-a-story&quot;&gt;The 1-B to the 1-A: Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story in a game is almost as important as gameplay. In fact, for certain games and genres, such as visual novels, it can be even more important than the gameplay itself. For others, story is far less important. But most of the time, both take the front seat of a game, with gameplay at the driver’s seat and story riding shotgun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While gameplay is the forefront of the game, grabbing all your attention, story takes the background and grabs your interest for the game. The setting, characters, dialogue, plot, and lore all contribute to getting your interest and keep you playing the game and to make you a fan of the game or franchise. I’d say gameplay is important for the immediate enjoyment of the game, but in the long run, I’d say that the story keeps you in and keeps people to like the game for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories in games take various forms, from emotional tearjerkers to over-the-top humor. Stories also differ from what the game intends to do with it. Visual novels and narrative driven games place story in the center of the game. Putting CrossCode in the limelight again, while the gameplay is the main entree, the story does not falter, and delivers a compelling story with likable characters, a interesting plot and decent setting all help give the game extra shine. Another title that I remember to have fantastic stroy or storytelling methods are NieR Automata, Other games, like DOOM, puts story more as side lore for the diehard fans to follow, and to find within the game as either side notes or easter eggs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these have in common to serve the purpose of the game. If the type of game calls for a story that isn’t right up in the player’s face, then a simple story with non-complex writing is fine. But if the game requires a deep story and lore, and fails to deliver on it, it really hurts the quality of the game. Poorly written dialogue, a shallow setting, and one-dimensional characters can all contribute to this. Another common pitfall is also the poor ending, where the game went along so well for most of the game only to collapse with a rushed and unsatisfactory ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to say is that not all games call for the deep story that we see as important. But when a game does need such a story, it really needs to deliver that to be called a good game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-backup---musicsound--graphics&quot;&gt;The backup - Music/Sound &amp;amp; Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If gameplay and story are at the front seats of the car getting to the destination, music and graphics are at the back seat for support. Both of them wouldn’t be able to save a game that has poor gameplay, story, or both. But it can elevate a game from good to excellent when both are used effectively. Between the two, I’d say music is more important to a game, but the case for graphics can also be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music in an already fleshed out game that has the gameplay and story down is crucial to seal the deal for it to be considered as a good game. The music works mostly with the story, and sometimes with the gameplay, to help accentuate areas in the game that need it. Character theme songs that fit the character writing, songs that cue in for scenarios to help the player feel the emotions the developer wanted, all depend on the game. A game without an appropriate soundtrack languishes as just an average game, while games with great ones are able to be ingrained in our minds as classics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some games that I find to have a stellar soundtrack that fits the game are NieR Automata, Hotline Miami, and Cave Story. While there are many other games that have a great soundtrack that I didn’t specify here, all of them make the most of them ingame to match the game at that point in time to great effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphics on the other hand is less of an importance for me quality wise. What is important for graphics is if the type of graphics fits the gameplay and story. The artstyle needs to be consistent and follow the game design of the rest of the game as well. The graphics don’t need to be fancy at all, as long as it is able to fit this requirement. Pixel-art graphics are fine, and may even add the the game experience more than if the artsyle was realistic, as long as it fits the feeling of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One great usage of graphics is Team Fortress 2. While the quality of the graphics in the game are nothing to write home about, the cartoonish, comedic artstyle of the game has allowed the game to stand out from other orthodox military shooters. This creative choice in graphics style alone has allowed it to have a longer lifespan than many other multiplayer shooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, graphics and music serve more of a supporting feature of games, to help good games become great or excellent ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-tidbits-and-dealbreakers&quot;&gt;Other tidbits and dealbreakers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming to the final spurt, there are some final tripwires that can cause a game to be excellent in all four areas spoken before, to absolutely hit rock bottom and become a dud. One of these is microtransactions, abbreviated as MTX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With microtransactions making itself known a lot more within games outside mobile ones, it needs to be said that one needs to be careful around them. If the MTX purchases makes a difference in the actual gameplay itself and not buying it gives you a disadvantage, then full stop, the game is probably not going to be good at all. Even if the game hits the spot for the other 4 qualities, a simple MTX inclusion of this kind can ruin the game, simply because you need to pay on top of the game’s original price to enjoy it. The most MTX purchases should be are cosmetic additions to your game, such as hats, skins, etc, and even those could be an issue for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another consideration for the game’s quality can be put through the idea of DLC and expansion packs. These two additions to a game can either make a game even better, or lower the quality as well. DLC and expansion packs, if well done, can add new features for gameplay, new stories and worlds to explore for the story, and much more that enhances the gameplay. The bigger additions are being seen more towards expansion packs, and really add a new aspect of games that can make a good game even better. However, DLC can also be used to put features that should have been in the original game in the first place under a paylock, only to accentuate the lower quality of a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many other factors that can be seen as factors that impact a game’s quality. Mod support, frequency of updates, and much more can affect a game. But I think I’ve gone through most of the qualities that do matter the most, and do feel that this is enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="games" /><summary type="html">Since writing up the past CrossCode and Factorio game review, I’ve been thinking about what makes a good game in the first place. What sorts from the good from the bad, and maybe from the good and the best? While thinking about this, I’ve thought of some “tier list”, or rather what matters the most when it comes to a good game, and what doesn’t matter as much.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New gear and changes to the EDC</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/08/29/New-gear-and-changes-to-the-EDC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New gear and changes to the EDC" /><published>2019-08-29T15:40:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-08-29T15:40:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/08/29/New%20gear%20and%20changes%20to%20the%20EDC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/2019/08/29/New-gear-and-changes-to-the-EDC.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://horseymask.github.io/personal/2019/07/11/The-EDC.html&quot;&gt;Original everyday carry (EDC) post here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With summer vacation coming to an end, I’ve decided to do some back-to-school shopping on the tech side. This semester is especially going to be travel heavy with no dorm to rely on, so I’ve bought some gear that’ll help me survive the more “road warrior” lifestyle I’ll go through this semester. Also, I’ve thinking of some changes to the EDC for this semester, which I’ll also get into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-new-gear&quot;&gt;The new gear&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-29edcupdate/20190829_144202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bluetooth Keyboard - Logitech K380&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got this keyboard refurbished, which was a great deal. Even if the keys don’t have Korean legends on them, I don’t type that much in Korean nor do I look at the keyboard when I type, so more power to me I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, I was planning to get the Logitech Slim Combo keyboard case, but the case was a lot more expensive than I wanted it to be. The case itself also added way too much bulk to the iPad, which was a bit unsightly. Worries about the kickstand and how well it’ll hold up from long sessions with the Apple Pencil was the final straw. From there, I looked to just get a cheaper, more universal bluetooth keyboard that I can use with devices other than the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back to the K380. Right now I’m typing this entry up on the iPad with the K380, and it’s not as bad as an experience that I thought it would be. I usually use a mechanical keyboard most of the time, and while comparing this keyboard to a mechanical one is unfair, the tactile feedback is quite acceptable, especially on the go. It’s definitely a productivity booster on the iPad, and makes the iPad a more formidable laptop replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue that I did face while typing is the circular keycap shapes. While it’s not as big of a deal as I make it, the circular keycaps does somewhat impact my typing speed and accuracy, as I am used to square keycaps. Also, the keyboard is a bit more low profile and lower that I am comfortable with, making typing a bit harder. Both of these things are probably stuff that I can get used to over time, so I think that I just need more time with this keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External Battery - Xiaomi Mi Power Bank 3 Pro, 20000mAh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one just arrived yesterday, along with a Quick Charge 3.0 (QC 3.0) + USB PD charging brick. While I didn’t really feel a need for a battery bank before, as I always had access to an outlet near me, whether it was at home, or at a dorm. But, with my phone’s battery draining a lot faster than the start of the first semester, and more time on the road this semester, I thought I’d need it this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first wanted a 26800mAh battery, as it allows for the most battery capacity while still being able to take on an airplane, but they turned out to be a lot rarer on the Korean markets. So I just settled with Xiaomi’s latest 20000mAh battery bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the spec sheet, the USB-A ports does look to match QC 3.0 standards, and the USB-C port supports USB-PD, which allows up to 45W of power delivery. This was what sold me, as I did want to have a battery bank that could support charging a laptop on the go. Though my current laptop doesn’t support USB-PD charging (I think), I thought it would be useful for the future. The USB-C will come in handy for charging my iPad though, as it does support USB-PD quick charging, and for my phone, which supports both QC and USB-PD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still need to put it to the test with the school year and facing conditions when I need to use it, but so far, it feels like a solid battery bank that I could rely on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-proposed-changes&quot;&gt;The (proposed) changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Laptop: &lt;del&gt;ASUS Zenbook UX310UQ&lt;/del&gt; No laptop at all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds crazy, right? A CS Student without a laptop on the go while studying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hear me out here though. I did say it was proposed changes. Nothing is final here. I realized that my laptop itself is pretty hefty with all the other stuff in my EDC bag. With a lot of movement expected next semester, I thought to myself if I could lessen the weight of the stuff I carry everyday, I can save a lot of effort while moving around. And so, I thought of taking my laptop out of my everyday carry in favor of the iPad, especially with the addition of the Logitech K380 keyboard, and possibly a wireless moue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are limitations with this choice. While the iPad is great for taking notes, drawing, writing (with a keyboard) and other kinds of lighter productivity tasks, there is one caveat: coding.  By itself, the iPad is very limited into code compilation and resources. There are certain apps such as Pythonista that does allow some coding, but there still is a lot of limitations, such as coding language choice. While iPadOS did make strides into making the iPad a laptop replacement, coding is still hard on it. I could also host a remote Visual Studio Code environment to use anywhere with the iPad, but that takes a lot of effort and also requires constant internet access. In the meantime, while I’m connected to the school network, I can SSH to write and compile my code using Vim on the university’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these limitations, I am planning to go through a week of using the iPad as my main device, when school starts. A lot of other people have tried doing this, with varying degrees of success depending on what their profession is and what their requirements were. I want to see how using the iPad as their main device as a CS student would be like. Taking it a step further, I can also ditch the desktop and only use the iPad as my computer device for the week. I know it probably won’t be very easy with all the limitations that I didn’t foresee, but I think it would be a great experience and a trial to see if the iPad can actually replace my laptop on an everyday carry basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other random bits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also decided to throw my old Magic Mouse that I purchased way back, as iPadOS now has mouse support, albeit pretty poor support. The scroll gestures don’t work for the Magic Mouse yet, and I guess that’s what I get for purchasing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the big proposed changes, there was a wallet change to a more compact one that is more focused on cards rather than bills. Very uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also was playing with the idea of a smartwatch, but the side of not investing in one is mostly winning just due to the price. The Galaxy Watch Active 2 did look pretty good though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8-29edcupdate/20190829_152950.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the final image of my updated EDC. You can check out the original EDC blogpost that I linked above for full details. I did keep the ASUS laptop in there for now because it still isn’t out just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that all from me this time with the updates.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Original everyday carry (EDC) post here</summary></entry></feed>